<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- This file is part of the SPFE Open Toolkit. See the accompanying license.txt file for applicable licenses.-->
<!-- (c) Copyright Analecta Communications Inc. 2012 All Rights Reserved. -->
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/css" href="../../../spfe-ot/plugins/eppo-simple/style/authoring/generic-task-topic.css"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/css" href="../../style/authoring/spfe-docs.css"?>
<generic-task-topic xmlns="http://spfeopentoolkit.org/spfe-docs/schemas/authoring/generic-task-topic"
    xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
    xsi:schemaLocation="http://spfeopentoolkit.org/spfe-docs/schemas/authoring/generic-task-topic
    http://spfeopentoolkit.org/spfe-docs/schemas/authoring/generic-task-topic.xsd">

    <head>
        <uri>http://spfeopentoolkit.org/spfe-docs/content/tasks/adding-a-topic.xml</uri>
        <author>jkeffer</author>
        <status>In progress</status>
        <history>
            <revision>
                <date>2013-06-14</date>
                <author>jkeffer</author>
                <comment>New topic</comment>
                <new-status>In progress</new-status>
            </revision>
        </history>
        <index>
            <entry>
                <type>feature</type>
                <term>new topic</term>
            </entry>
            <entry>
                <type>task</type>
                <term>adding a topic</term>
            </entry>
        </index>
    </head>
    <body>
        <title>Adding a new topic</title>
        <understanding>
            <p>A new topic is a new web page or a new section in a print document. A topic must
                follow a schema and it must belong to a topic-set. A topic appears under the
                topic-set folder in an HTML document or as an entry in a print document's table of
                contents.</p>
       </understanding>
       <planning>
           <planning-question>
               <planning-question-title>What do I need before adding a new topic?</planning-question-title>
                <planning-question-body>
                   <p>Before you add a topic, you must decide whether to use an existing schema or
                        whether to use a new schema.</p>
                    <ul>
                        <li>
                        <p> If you add your topic to an existing topic-set, your topic must use the
                                corresponding schema.</p>
                        </li>
                        <li><p>If your topic uses a new schema, you must first <task>add a topic-set</task>.</p>
                        </li>
                    </ul>
                </planning-question-body>
                <how-to-answer-body>
                    <p>Based on the content of your topic, determine if you can use an existing custom schema or an EPPO simple schema.</p>
                </how-to-answer-body>
            </planning-question>
       </planning>
<doing>
    <p>Create a new file for your topic and follow the schema you selected to add your content. Be
                sure to validate your XML content before building the documents. If your content is
                invalid, the <feature>doc-set</feature> or <feature>topic-set</feature> will build,
                but it will not include the new topic. To add the topic to a topic-setc:</p>
            <ul>
                <li>
                    <p>If you store your topic source file in a directory that is already included
                        in the topic-set configuration file, the build automatically adds the topic
                        to the document.</p>
                </li>
                <li>
                    <p>If you store your topic file in a new directory, add the new directory path
                        to the <![CDATA[<sources>]]> element of the topic-set configuration file.</p>
                </li>
            </ul>
    <p>When you build your documents, if your topic appears in the output under the correct topic-set and contains the correct content, you have successfully added a topic to a topic-set.</p>
        </doing>
    </body>
</generic-task-topic>
