<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- This file is part of the SPFE Open Toolkit. See the accompanying license.txt file for applicable licenses.-->
<!-- (c) Copyright Analecta Communications Inc. 2012 All Rights Reserved. -->

<feature-topic xmlns="http://spfeopentoolkit.org/ns/eppo-simple"
    xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
    xsi:schemaLocation="http://spfeopentoolkit.org/ns/eppo-simple http://spfeopentoolkit.org/spfe-docs/topic-types/feature-topic/schemas/feature-topic.xsd">
    <head>
        <id>feature-topic-sets</id>
        <history>
            <revision>
                <date>2014-06-23</date>
                <author>mbaker</author>
                <comment>New Topic</comment>
                <status>In progress</status>
            </revision>
        </history>
        <index>
            <entry>
                <type>feature</type>
                <term>topic set</term>
            </entry>
            <entry>
                <type>feature</type>
                <term>topic sets</term>
            </entry>
            
        </index>
    </head>
    <body>
        <title>Topic sets</title>
        <p>In SPFE, a <feature>documentation set</feature> consists of one of more <feature>topic sets</feature>. A topic set is a collection of topics, usually on a related subject. In a book-based environment, a topic set would be similar to a manual, in the sense that a paper-based documentation systems is made up of books or manuals. However, SPFE does not presume that a topic set constitutes a manual. It is simply a collection of related topics, and how the topics in the toic set are related to each other is up to the information architect.</p>
        <p>A topic set may be made up of individual topics written by authors. It may also be made up of topics <task>generated from external sources</task>, or of a <task>combination of written and generated sources</task>. In the case of topic sets created from external sources, you can also merge written content with the extracted content to form complete topics. This is a common approach to creating a reference document.</p>
        <p>A <task>topic set is defined</task> by a <feature>topic set configuration file</feature> using the configuration setting <config-setting>/spfe/topic-set</config-setting>. The topic set configuration specifies the topics t be included in the topic set. However, you should not think of this simply as a list of topics files to include. Instead, this of this as a query that returns a set of topics that meet a specific set of conditions. A topic may be added to a topic set simply by creating a topic that meets the conditions for inclusion in a particular topic set.</p>
        <p>Because a topic set is simply a configuration of topics, you can have more than one topic-set configuration that includes the same or a similar set of topics. You can do this as a means of <task>reusing topics</task>, or simply to create different build variations.</p>
    </body>
</feature-topic>