<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- This file is part of the SPFE Open Toolkit. See the accompanying license.txt file for applicable licenses.-->
<!-- (c) Copyright Analecta Communications Inc. 2012 All Rights Reserved. -->

<feature-topic xmlns="http://spfeopentoolkit.org/ns/spfe-docs"
    xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
    xsi:schemaLocation="http://spfeopentoolkit.org/ns/spfe-docs http://spfeopentoolkit.org/spfe-docs/topic-types/feature-topic/schemas/feature-topic.xsd">
    <head>
        <id>feature-presentation</id>
        <history>
            <revision>
                <date>2014-06-23</date>
                <author>mbaker</author>
                <comment>New Topic</comment>
                <status>In progress</status>
            </revision>
        </history>
        <index>
            <entry>
                <type>feature</type>
                <term>presentation</term>
            </entry>
            <entry>
                <type>feature</type>
                <term>presentation process</term>
            </entry>
        </index>
    </head>
    <body>
        <title>Presentation</title>
        <p>The <feature>presentation</feature> step is the second phase of the <feature>SPFE build</feature> process. It is responsible for creating the final text, organization, and behavior of the <feature>topics</feature> in a <feature>topic set</feature>. In essence, it is responsible for the information architecture of the topic set.</p>
        <p>The presentation step take the set of topics created by the synthesis stage and prepares them to be presented in a particular information design. You may decide to present topics differently for different media. For instance, you may have one presentation routine that prepares topics for presentation online in media such as the Web, another for a local help system, and another that prepares the same topics to be presented in a static linear media such as paper or a PDF. The ability to apply different forms of presentation means you don't have to have your Web output arranged like your help systems or your PDF.</p>
        <p>The output of the presentation step becomes the input to the <feature>formatting</feature> step, which is responsible for the appearance of the content in a particular media, such as HTML or PDF.</p>
    </body>
</feature-topic>