<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- This file is part of the SPFE Open Toolkit. See the accompanying license.txt file for applicable licenses.-->
<!-- (c) Copyright Analecta Communications Inc. 2012 All Rights Reserved. -->
<content-set-home-topic xmlns="http://spfeopentoolkit.org/ns/spfe-docs"
    xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
    xsi:schemaLocation="http://spfeopentoolkit.org/ns/spfe-docs http://spfeopentoolkit.org/spfe-docs/topic-types/content-set-home-topic/schemas/authoring/content-set-home-topic.xsd">
    <head>
        <id>index</id>
        <history>
            <revision>
                <date>2012-04-22</date>
                <author>mbaker</author>
                <comment>New topic</comment>
                <status>In progress</status>
            </revision>
        </history>
        <index>
            <entry>
                <type>document-name</type>
                <term>SPFE Development</term>
            </entry>
        </index>
    </head>
    <body>
        <title>SPFE Open Toolkit Documentation</title>
        <p>The <string-ref id-ref="product"/> is a toolkit for building
            content creation systems using the <feature>SPFE architecture</feature>. </p>
        <p>The SPFE architecture is designed to facilitate the creation of structured writing
            systems that use a <concept>bottom-up information architecture</concept>. </p>
        <p>Bottom-up information architectures are common on the Web. Both wikis and blogging
            platforms, as well as many Web CMS work on the bottom-up pattern. However, there are no
            bottom-up systems based on markup-based structured writing principles (some
            database-based structured bottom-up systems exist). The <string-ref id-ref="product"/>
            is designed to fill this gap.</p>
        <p>The SPFE-OT is also capable of creating
            <concept specifically="top-down information architecture">top-down</concept> and
            hybrid <concept specifically="top-down information architecture">top-down</concept>/<concept specifically="bottom-up information architecture">bottom-up information architectures</concept>.</p>
        <section>
            <title>Writing in a SPFE Environment</title>
            <p>SPFE is intended to make structured writing as simple as possible for writers by
                minimizing how much they need to understand about the publishing system, and by
                minimizing the need to understand to interact with the overall body of content that
                an organization maintains. Traditional content management approaches of ten require
                substantial knowledge of both the system itself and the whole corpus of content in
                order to participate fully in content creation. SPFE is designed to avoid this by
                creating a publish and content management environment that is driven by
                <concept>metadata</concept> about the subject matter of the content -- something
                that the author naturally understands.</p>
            <p>Structured authoring is also easier if the structures that authors are asked to
                create are simple and related as specifically as possible to the subject matter they
                are writing about. SPFE is designed to work best with small subject-specific
                structures, and to make it as easy as possible to
                <task specifically="create structures">design and implement such structures</task>.</p>
        </section>
<section>
    <title>Schemas</title>
    <p>As a <concept>structured writing system</concept>, SPFE works with content that conforms to a
                set of formal rules known as a <concept>schema</concept>. Schemas define which
                content structures can be used in which situations. Successful
                <task>processing of content</task> depends on the content conforming to both the
                letter and the spirit of the appropriate schema. </p>
    <p>However, unlike the DocBook and DITA systems, SPFE is not based on a particular schema. Rather,
            SPFE is a modular content processing architecture that can be used with a variety of
            schemas. However, SPFE does make certain presumptions about how schemas will be
                written. In particular it expects a <concept specifically="declarative markup">declarative style of
                markup</concept> in which the document markup does not contain any publishing or
            content management directives. </p>
        <p>To enable users to get up to speed quickly, and to provide a baseline of functionality
            for building SPFE-compatible schemas, <string-ref id-ref="product"
            /> includes the <feature>EPPO Simple</feature> schema set. EPPO Simple is a highly
            modularized set of schemas and associated processing that you can use directly or as the
            basis for <task>creating your own schemas</task>.</p>
</section>    </body>
</content-set-home-topic>
