<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- This file is part of the SPFE Open Toolkit. See the accompanying license.txt file for applicable licenses.-->
<!-- (c) Copyright Analecta Communications Inc. 2012 All Rights Reserved. -->
<think-plan-do-topic xmlns="http://spfeopentoolkit.org/ns/spfe-docs"
    xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
    xsi:schemaLocation="http://spfeopentoolkit.org/ns/spfe-docs
    http://spfeopentoolkit.org/spfe-docs/topic-types/think-plan-do-topic/schemas/authoring/think-plan-do-topic.xsd">

    <head>
        <id>adding-a-topic</id>
        <history>
            <revision>
                <date>2013-06-14</date>
                <author>jkeffer</author>
                <comment>New topic</comment>
                <status>In progress</status>
            </revision>
            <revision>
                <date>2013-06-14</date>
                <author>jkeffer</author>
                <comment>Remove some incorrect content.</comment>
                <status>In progress</status>
            </revision>
            <revision>
                <date>2013-06-21</date>
                <author>jkeffer</author>
                <comment>Remove some incorrect content.</comment>
                <status>Ready for technical review</status>
            </revision>
            <revision>
                <date>2014-06-17</date>
                <author>mbaker</author>
                <comment>Fixing config-setting references</comment>
                <status>In progress</status>
            </revision>
        </history>
        <index>
            <entry>
                <type>feature</type>
                <term>topic</term>
            </entry>
            <entry>
                <type>task</type>
                <term>{add} a {topic}</term>
            </entry>
        </index>
    </head>
    <body>
        <title>Adding a new topic</title>
        <understanding>
            <p>A <feature>topic</feature> is the basic unit of content that is presented to the user. If you are trying to create a reusable content building block that is not a full topic, you should be creating a <feature>fragment</feature>, a <feature>string</feature>, or a <feature>object</feature>.</p>
       </understanding>
       <planning>
           <planning-question>
               <planning-question-title>Which topic type should I use?</planning-question-title>
                <planning-question-body>
                   <p>Before you add a topic, you must decide what <feature>topic type</feature> to
                        create. You should choose the topic type that is most specific to the
                        subject matter you are writing about. You should also be aware that each
                        topic set only allows a specific set to topic types to be included. While
                        you don't create topics for topic sets, but as independent entities, you
                        don't want to be surprised by this requirement down the line.  Each
                            <feature>topic set configuration file</feature> lists the topic types
                        that are allowed in that topic set.  That list should reflect the type of
                        content the topic set is supposed to contain, so if the best topic type for
                        your subject matter is not one that a topic set that wants to include it
                        supports, the chances are that the problem lies with how the topic set is
                        defined rather than with the topic type chosen for the topic.</p>
                </planning-question-body>
            </planning-question>
       </planning>
<doing>
    <p>To add a new topic, create a file based on the schema for the topic type you have chosen.</p>
            <p>Where you store your file will depend on the rules of the repository that you are
                using. In the simplest case, you will store you file in a directory on the local
                file system. One or more topic sets may be set up to pull files from that directory,
                in which case you topic will then be included in those topic sets. In other cases,
                the file may be included or excluded based on metadata it contains.</p>
        </doing>
    </body>
</think-plan-do-topic>
