<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- This file is part of the SPFE Open Toolkit. See the accompanying license.txt file for applicable licenses.-->
<!-- (c) Copyright Analecta Communications Inc. 2012 All Rights Reserved. -->
<think-plan-do-topic xmlns="http://spfeopentoolkit.org/ns/spfe-docs" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://spfeopentoolkit.org/ns/spfe-docs
http://spfeopentoolkit.org/spfe-docs/topic-types/think-plan-do-topic/schemas/authoring/think-plan-do-topic.xsd">

    <head>
        <id>adding-a-structure-to-your-project</id>
        <history>
            <revision>
                <date>2015-01-24</date>
                <author>mbaker</author>
                <comment>New topic</comment>
                <status>In progress</status>
            </revision>
        </history>
        <index>
            <entry>
                <type>feature</type>
                <term>structure</term>
            </entry>
            <entry>
                <type>task</type>
                <term>{add} a {structure}</term>
            </entry>
            <entry>
                <type>config-setting</type>
                <term>/structure</term>
            </entry>
        </index>
    </head>
    <body>
        <title>Adding a new structure</title>
        <understanding>
            <p>A <feature>structure</feature> is a collection of document structure elements that
                work together to provide some distinct text structure such as a
                    <eppo-simple-structure-name>list</eppo-simple-structure-name> or a
                    <eppo-simple-structure-name>table</eppo-simple-structure-name>. A
                <feature>topic type</feature> is made up of an appropriate collection of structures.
                EPPO-simple provides a selection of structures that you can use to create
                <feature>topic types</feature> for your <feature>content set</feature>. In some
                cases, however, you may want to create a new structure specifically for one or more
                topic types in your content set. </p>
            <p>For example, the SPFE Docs include a demo topic type which is designed to show how
                various features of SPFE and EPPO-simple are used. Demo topics need to show samples
                of the output produced by these features. To enable the formatting routines to set
                these samples apart from ordinary text, it uses an output-sample structure. This
                structure is not needed in most topic types in the SPFE docs, and is certainly not
                needed by most content sets unless they describe structured text systems like
                SPFE.</p>
       </understanding>
       <planning>
           <planning-question>
               <planning-question-title>Do I need a custom structure?</planning-question-title>
                <planning-question-body>
                    <p>In many cases, it is possible to use an existing structure that will produce
                        the output effect you are looking for, or something close enough to it.
                        Given this, is it worth creating a custom structure. For instance, the SPFE
                        Docs could have used a generic
                        <xml-element-name>blockquote</xml-element-name> element to contain and
                        output sample. Some reasons to create a custom structure are:</p>
                    <ll>
                        <li>
                            <label>Greater clarity</label>
                            <p>A custom structure more clearly expresses what the content it contain
                                means. This helps authors, editors, and downstream processes to
                                process the structure correctly.</p>
                        </li>
                        <li>
                            <label>More specific structure</label>
                            <p>You can express more precise structural requirements with a custom
                                structure. Parts of a generic structure may be optional whereas you
                                want them to be required in your custom structure. You can also
                                require or allow the custom structure at more specific places in
                                your topic type. This also makes it easier to <task>audit and
                                    validate your content</task>. </p>
                        </li>
                    </ll>
                    <ll>
                        <li>
                            <label>More formatting control</label>
                            <p>Creating a custom structure makes it easy to specify <task>specific
                                    formatting for the structure in different media</task>.</p>
                        </li>
                    </ll>
                </planning-question-body>
            </planning-question>
            <planning-question>
                <planning-question-title>Why not just use an attribute to modify the handling of an existing structure</planning-question-title>
                <planning-question-body>
                    <p>Many structured text vocabularies use generic structures and then use
                        attributes on the root element of those structures to designate a more
                        specific type. For instance, in DITA, admonitions are indicated with a
                        generic note element with a type elements that indicates the type of
                        admonition:
                        <code>note | tip | fastpath | restriction | important | remember | attention | caution | danger | other</code>.
                        EPPO-simple, on the other hand, supplies different sets of admonition
                        structures for different purposes. For instance, if you add the
                            <eppo-simple-structure-name>admonitions.danger-warning-caution-notice</eppo-simple-structure-name>
                        structure to your topic type, you will get for separate admonition
                        structures: danger, warning, caution, and notice. There are a number of
                        advantages to this approach:</p>
                    <ll>
                        <li>
                            <label>Easier to author</label>
                            <p>If an author wants to add a warning to a piece of text is easier to
                                think <quotes>Warning</quotes> than to think
                                <quotes>note with a warning attribute</quotes> and it is easier to
                                create a warning element than to create a note element and add a
                                warning attribute. </p>
                        </li>
                        <li>
                            <label>Better guidance</label>
                            <p>For any given subject matter, topic type, content set, or company
                                style, only certain sets of admonitions are appropriate. You don't
                                want authors to have to remember which are allowed and which are not
                                allowed from a large set. You only want them to have the appropriate
                                ones available. </p>
                        </li>
                    </ll>
                </planning-question-body>
            </planning-question>
           <planning-question>
               <planning-question-title>Should I create a custom structure in my content set project or as a SPFE-OT plugin</planning-question-title>
               <planning-question-body>
                   <p>You can define a custom structure within you content project or you can make
                        it a separate plugin. If the structure is unique to a particular content
                        set, create it there. If it is potentially usuable for several content sets,
                        make it a plugin. If you think it is potentially useful to others and you
                        are willing to share, you could <task>submit it to the SPFE Open
                            Toolkit</task> for possible inclusion in the standard structures
                        distributed with the toolkit. </p>
               </planning-question-body>
           </planning-question>
       </planning>
        <doing>        
            <p>To create a custom structure:</p>
            <procedure>
                <title>Creating a custom structure</title>
                <intro>
                    <p>This is the high-level procedure for creating a custom structure.</p>
                </intro>
                <steps>
                    <step>
                        <title>Create the structure directory</title>
                        <p>Select the appropriate location for your structure and create a
                                <feature>structure directory</feature> there. If you want to create
                            more than one version of a structure, create a main structure directory
                            for this class of structure and one subdirectory for each specific type
                            of this class. For an example, see the EPPO-simple admonitions
                            structure, which contains a variety of different specific admonitions
                            structures for various collections of admonitions.</p>
                        <p>Unless it is a parent directory for different variation on the structure,
                            each structure directory contain a config file and three directories:
                            schemas, scripts, and style. (But not every structure needs to define
                            all these things, so you may not need all three directories in each
                            case.)</p>
                    </step>
                    <step>
                        <title>Create an authoring schema for your structure</title>
                        <p/>
                    </step>
                    <step>
                        <title>Create one or more presentation schemas for your structure</title>
                        <p/>
                    </step>
                    <step>
                        <title>Create scripts for processing your structure</title>
                        <p/>
                    </step>
                    <step>
                        <title>Create CSS stylesheets for authoring and displaying your
                            structure</title>
                        <p/>
                    </step>
                    <step>
                        <title>Create a configuration file for your structure</title>
                        <p/>
                    </step>
                    <step>
                        <title>Add your structure to your topic type</title>
                        <p/>
                    </step>
                </steps>
            </procedure>
        </doing>
    </body>
</think-plan-do-topic>
