<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<think-plan-do-topic xmlns="http://spfeopentoolkit.org/ns/spfe-docs"
    xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
    xsi:schemaLocation="http://spfeopentoolkit.org/ns/spfe-docs 
    http://spfeopentoolkit.org/spfe-docs/topic-types/think-plan-do-topic/schemas/authoring/think-plan-do-topic.xsd">

    <head>
        <id>configuring-spfe-ot</id>
        <history>
            <revision>
                <date>2014-11-26</date>
                <author>jfmacdonald</author>
                <comment>New topic</comment>
                <status>In progress</status>
            </revision>
            <revision>
                <date>2014-11-30</date>
                <author>jfmacdonald</author>
                <comment>New topic</comment>
                <status>Ready for technical review</status>
            </revision>
        </history>
        <index>
            <entry>
                <type>task</type>
                <term>configure</term>
            </entry>
            <entry>
                <type>feature</type>
                <term>content set</term>
            </entry>
            <entry>
                <type>feature</type>
                <term>topic set</term>
            </entry>
        </index>
    </head>
    <body>
        <title>Configuring SPFE Open Toolkit</title>

        <understanding>

            <p> The <feature> SPFE Open Toolkit </feature> (SPFE-OT) must be configured to control
                how it builds output from source XML markup. One or more configuration files
                specifies which source content will be processed, how it will be processed, and how
                it will be organized and linked. Together, the configuration files are the master
                plan for a SPFE build. SPFE has a distributed configuration model. Every component
                of the system has a configuration file, and you can assemble your configuration by
                including the configuration file for the components you use.</p>

            <p> SPFE Open Toolkit configuration consists of the following configuration  file
                types:</p>
            <ll>
                <li>
                    <label>Content set configuration file:</label>
                    <p>The top-level configuration file used to build a
                        <feature>content set</feature>. The
                        <feature>content set configuration file</feature> specifies the
                        <feature>topic sets</feature> to be included in the content set and the
                        <feature>output formats</feature> to be built.  </p>
                </li>
                <li>
                    <label>Topic set configuration file:</label>
                    <p>The configuration for a <feature>topic set</feature>. It specifies the
                        criteria for including topics in a topic set (generally this is not a fixed
                        list of topics. A topic set configuration file does not have to be updated
                        every time a new topic is created. All the topics that meet the specified
                        criteria are included automatically.) The
                        <feature>topic-set configuration file</feature> also specifies the
                        <feature>topic types</feature> that can occur in the topic set and the
                        <feature>type of outputs</feature> to create for it. (The content set
                        specified specific output configurations for the content set; the topic set
                        configuration specifies which of the available configuration to build for
                        the individual content set.)</p>
                </li>
                <li>
                    <label>Topic type configuration file</label>
                    <p>The configuration for a <feature>topic type</feature>. Provides a name for
                        the <feature>topic type</feature> and specifies the set of
                        <feature>structures</feature> used in the topic type and the set of scripts
                        used for <task>processing a topic</task> of this type through each of the
                        <feature>SPFE processing stages</feature>.</p>
                </li>
                <li>
                    <label>Output type configuration file</label>
                    <p>The configuration of an <feature>output type</feature>. Specifies the name of
                        the output type and scripts used to build the output. Note that you could
                        configure more than one output type configuration for the same output type.
                        For instance, you could configure two different styles of HTML output. You
                        could then point whichever configuration you wanted to build from the
                        content set <feature>configuration file</feature>. If both these
                        configurations had the name <quotes>html</quotes>, topic set configuration
                        files that specified <quotes>html</quotes> as an output format would not
                        need to change when you built different HTML outputs. </p>
                </li>
                <li>
                    <label>Structure configuration file</label>
                    <p>The configuration file for a <feature>structure</feature>. Specifies the
                        scripts to be used for processing a particular structure. Using structures
                        make it easy to configure a topic type by including existing structures.
                        Note that you may want to provide more than one configuration file for a
                        structure, if you want the same structured to be processed differently in
                        different circumstances. While a structure directory will generally include
                        a  default structure configuration file, as well as default processing
                        scripts, you are free to create your own structure configuration files for
                        any structure that point to your own processing scripts for that structure.
                        Some <feature>EPPO simple</feature> structures come with more than one
                        structured configuration file for different purposes.</p>
                </li>
                <li>
                    <label>Presentation type configuration</label>
                    <p>The configuration file for the presentation stage of the SPFE build. Most
                        <feature specifically="topic type configuration">topic type</feature> and
                        <feature>structure configurations</feature> will contain the
                        <feature>presentation configuration</feature> for the presentation types
                        that the author of the topic type or structure was aware of at the time they
                        wrote them. If you wanted to specify a new presentation format for an
                        existing topic type or structure you could do so either by writing entirely
                        new topic type and structure configurations, or by writing a separate
                        presentation type configuration file. </p>
                </li>
                <li>
                    <label>Object type configuration files</label>
                    <p>The
                        <feature specifically="object configration file">configuration file</feature>
                        for an <feature>object</feature>. Does the same thing for object types that
                        the <feature>topic type configuration file</feature> does for
                        <feature>topic types</feature> and the
                        <feature>structure configuration file</feature> does for
                        <feature>structures</feature>. </p>
                </li>
            </ll>
            <p/>

            <p> To create a body of content, an author will need to be concerned with the first two,
                content set and topic set configurations, which identify content sources.
                Configuring topic types and output formats is not content specific and should be
                done beforehand by a SPFE Open Toolkit developer.</p>

        </understanding>

        <planning>
            <planning-question>
                <planning-question-title>Where should the configuration files be located</planning-question-title>
                <planning-question-body>
                    <p>The content set and topic set configuration files may reside anywhere in the
                        files system that is convenient. References to configuration, source, and
                        other files may be relative or absolute path names. A common setup has the
                        content set configuration file in the working directory, where the
                        <code>spfe</code> command will be executed and log files kept, with topic
                        set configuration files and content files in subdirectories and referenced
                        with relative paths. This way the entire set can be relocated without
                        needing to edit configuration files. </p>
                </planning-question-body>
            </planning-question>

        </planning>

        <doing>

            <p> Create a <feature>content set</feature> configuration XML file
                in the directory you will execute the <feature>spfe</feature> command to create
                builds or any convenient location. Use the <config-setting> /content-set
                </config-setting> XML structure. </p>

            <p> Create a <feature>topic set</feature> configuration XML file for each topic set
                using the <config-setting>/topic-set</config-setting> XML structure. </p>

            <p> Create a <feature>topic type</feature> configuration XML file for each topic type
                using the <config-setting>/topic-type</config-setting> XML structure. </p>

            <p> Create a <feature>output-format</feature> configuration XML file for each output
                format using the <config-setting>/output-format</config-setting> XML structure.
            </p>

        </doing>

    </body> 
</think-plan-do-topic>
