<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<think-plan-do-topic xmlns="http://spfeopentoolkit.org/ns/spfe-docs"
    xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
    xsi:schemaLocation="http://spfeopentoolkit.org/ns/spfe-docs 
    http://spfeopentoolkit.org/spfe-docs/topic-types/think-plan-do-topic/schemas/authoring/think-plan-do-topic.xsd">
 
    <head>
        <id>configuring-content-sets</id>
        <history>
            <revision>
                <date>2014-11-30</date>
                <author>jfmacdonald</author>
                <comment>New topic</comment>
                <status>In progress</status>
            </revision>
            <revision>
                <date>2014-11-30</date>
                <author>jfmacdonald</author>
                <comment>New topic</comment>
                <status>Ready for technical review</status>
            </revision>
        </history>
        <index>
            <entry>
                <type>task</type>
                <term>configure</term>
            </entry>
            <entry>
                <type>feature</type>
                <term>content set</term>
            </entry>
        </index>
    </head>
    <body>
        <title>Configuring content sets</title>

        <understanding>

            <p> The <feature>SPFE Open Toolkit</feature> (SPFE-OT) must be configured to
                control how it builds output from source XML markup. The content set configuration
                is an XML structure that specifies which content will be included in a SPFE-OT
                build. </p>

            <p> The content set configuration file will be the entry point for the build process; it
                will be specified as the first argument of the <file-name>spfe</file-name> command
                that starts the build process. The content set configuration file references
                <feature> topic set </feature> configuration files that specify individual topics.
                The SPFE build system processes each topic set as a unit. </p>
            
            <p> The SPFE build system will, by default, organize topics hierarchically with topic
                sets in separate groups and topics organized by topic type within a topic set. The
                build system will generate table of contents (TOC) with this organization to aid
                navigation. These TOCs are not the only navigation aids the build system generates;
                the system also creates subject-affinity links (<feature>soft links</feature>)
                and subject index lists. Nevertheless, hierarchical navigation is one way that
                content users will find what they want.</p>
        
        </understanding>

        <planning>
            <planning-question>
                <planning-question-title>Where should the configuration files reside?</planning-question-title>
                <planning-question-body><p> Content set and topic set configuration files may reside anywhere in the
                filesystem that is convenient for the author. References to configuration, source,
                and other files may be relative or absolute path names. A common setup has the
                content set configuration file in the working directory, where the <code>spfe
                </code> command will be executed and log files kept, with topic set configuration
                files and content files in subdirectories and referenced with relative paths. This
                way the entire set can be relocated without needing to edit configuration files.</p></planning-question-body>
            </planning-question>
            
            

           

        </planning>

        <doing>

            <p> Create a <feature>content set</feature> configuration XML file
                in the directory you will execute the <feature>spfe</feature> command to create
                builds or any convenient location. Use the <config-setting> /content-set
                </config-setting> XML structure shown in the example that follows. </p>

            <subhead>Required settings</subhead>

            <p> Set the following in the content set configuration in the order listed:</p>

            <ul>
                <li>
                    <p> <config-setting>/content-set/content-set-id</config-setting>: A unique
                        content set identifier, which will be the name of the sub-directory under
                        the <feature>SPFE_BUILD_DIR</feature> directory where the content set will
                        be generated. </p>
                </li>
                <li>
                    <p> <config-setting>/content-set/title</config-setting>: The title that
                        will appear on the generated home page for the content set.</p>
                </li>
                <li>
                    <p> <config-setting>/content-set/home-topic-set</config-setting>:
                        Set the topic that will be the home or first page in the content set's
                        output. The home topic set must be among the listed topic sets.</p>
                </li>
                <li>
                    <p> <config-setting>/content-set/topic-sets</config-setting>:
                        List the topic sets to be included in the content set.</p>
                </li>
                <li>
                    <p> <config-setting>/content-set/subject-types</config-setting>:
                        Specify the <feature>subject-affinity</feature>tags that the build system
                        may recognize in forming subject-affinity lists. Topics may include an index
                        of terms, each of which is associated with a subject type defined in the
                        content set configuration, so that they may become the target of <feature>
                        soft linking</feature>.</p>
                </li>
            </ul>

            <subhead>Optional settings</subhead>

            <p> Set optional items in the content set configuration in the order listed. An option 
                that is not used does not need to be set; just leave it out:</p>

            <ul>
                <li>
                    <p> <config-setting>/content-set/condition-tokens</config-setting>:
                        Specify tokens for conditional inclusion of content <feature>fragments
                        </feature> in output.</p>
                </li>
                <li>
                    <p> <config-setting>/content-set/messages</config-setting>: Specify
                        the type of messages (info and warning) to include in the build log.</p>
                </li>
                <li>
                    <p> <config-setting>/content-set/output-formats</config-setting>:
                        Specify output formats.</p>
                </li>
                <li>
                    <p> <config-setting>/content-set/strings</config-setting>:
                        Identify strings that may be included in content when referenced.</p>
                </li>
            </ul>


            <subhead>Content set example configuration</subhead>
            <fragment-ref id-ref="content-set-example" />

            <p></p>
        </doing>

    </body> 
</think-plan-do-topic>
