<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<generic-topic xmlns="http://spfeopentoolkit.org/ns/spfe-docs"
    xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
    xsi:schemaLocation="http://spfeopentoolkit.org/ns/spfe-docs 
    http://spfeopentoolkit.org/spfe-docs/topic-types/essay/schemas/essay.xsd">

    <head>
        <id>how-does-spfe-ot-work</id>
        <history>
            <revision>
                <date>2014-11-02</date>
                <author>jfmacdonald</author>
                <comment>New topic</comment>
                <status>In progress</status>
            </revision>
            <revision>
                <date>2014-11-30</date>
                <author>jfmacdonald</author>
                <comment>New topic</comment>
                <status>Ready for technical review</status>
            </revision>
        </history>
        <index>
            <entry>
                <type>feature</type>
                <term>XML</term>
            </entry>
            <entry>
                <type>feature</type>
                <term>XML Schema</term>
            </entry>
            <entry>
                <type>feature</type>
                <term>XSLT</term>
            </entry>
            <entry>
                <type>feature</type>
                <term>synthesis</term>
            </entry>
            <entry>
                <type>feature</type>
                <term>presentation</term>
            </entry>
            <entry>
                <type>feature</type>
                <term>formatting</term>
            </entry>
            <entry>
                <type>feature</type>
                <term>encoding</term>
            </entry>
            <entry>
                <type>feature</type>
                <term>spfe script</term>
            </entry>
            <entry>
                <type>feature</type>
                <term>SPFE Open Toolkit</term>
            </entry>
            <entry>
                <type>file-name</type>
                <term>spfe</term>
            </entry>
        </index>
    </head>
    <body>
        <title>How does the SPFE Open Toolkit work?</title>

        <p> The <feature>SPFE Open Toolkit</feature> is a system for transforming
            <feature>structured content</feature> XML to produce output in a desired format.  It
            works by processing source XML through a series of stages to produce the output:</p>

        <ol>

            <li> <p> In a prepatory configuration stage, the toolkit creates or updates the build
                    directory, collects and merges all configuration files, and creates the
                    <tool-name> Ant </tool-name> build file that will govern the build process.</p>
            </li>

            <li> <p> The <feature>synthesis</feature> stage collects source <feature>topics
            </feature>, pulling content together for further processing.</p> </li>

            <li> <p> The <feature>presentation</feature> stage organizes and links topics,
                    structuring content as needed for a particular output format.</p> </li>

            <li> <p> The <feature>formatting</feature> stage produces an XML representation of the
                    format. If the output format is an XML format, such as XHTML, this will be the
                    final stage.</p> </li>

            <li> <p> The <feature>encoding</feature> stage tranforms the XML representation to the
                    output format when that format, such as PDF, is not XML.</p> </li>

        </ol>

        <p> Understanding the SPFE build process will help you use the toolkit and resolve problems
            when they occur.</p>

        <section>
            <title>Configuration stage</title>

            <p> A toolkit build begins by creating or updating a subdirectory of the <feature>
                    SPFE_BUILD_DIR</feature> directory for the content set and creating an
                <tool-name> Ant</tool-name> build file, <code>$SPFE_BUILD_DIR/spfebuild.xml</code>.
                The build directory for the content set,
                <code>$SPFE_BUILD_DIR/&lt;content-set-id&gt;</code>, contains the following: </p>

            <ul>

                <li> <p> A merged SPFE configuration file, <code>config/spfe-config.xml</code>.</p>
                </li>

                <li> <p> A collection of XSLT scripts for each <feature>topic set</feature> that
                        will be used in the build. The scripts are in subdirectories of <code>
                            content-set-id/build/topic-sets/&lt;topic-set-id&gt;/</code>, with a
                        subdirectory for scripts used in subsequent build stages.</p> </li>

            </ul>

        </section>

        <section>
            <title>Synthesis stage</title>

            <p> The synthesis stage collects and identifies each component of content to ensure that
                it's available for the build. References and conditionals are resolved, fragments
                and other objects imported, and content from external sources is extracted.  The
                synthesis stage also creates a table of contents and link catalog for each topic
                set. </p>

            <p> Link catalogs identify topics for <feature> subject-affinity linking </feature>.
                Each <feature> topic set</feature> is processed in the order listed in the <feature>
                    content set </feature> configuration. The order is signficant, because the link
                catalogs produced for each topic set are available when processing subsequent topic
                sets for <feature> soft linking </feature>. </p>

            <p> The synthesis stage produces an XML file for each topic set with the synthesis
                output of its topic's content, <code>
                    content-set-id/build/topic-sets/&lt;topic-set-id&gt;/resolve/out/synthesis.xml
                </code>, a link-catalog file, <code>
                content-set-id/build/link-catalogs/&lt;topic-set-id&gt;.link-catalog.xml </code>,
                and table-of-contents file, <code>
                content-set-id/build/tocs/&lt;topic-set-id&gt;.toc.xml </code>. </p>

        </section>
        <section>

            <title>Presentation stage</title>

            <p> The presentation stage organizes and prepares topics for presentation in the
                selected output format. The preparation here is structural; actual formatting occurs
                in next stage. Here, the build process interprets each topic's <feature> metadata
                </feature> according to its topic type that's set by its <feature> XML Schema
                </feature> and maps the topic structure into structures appropriate for the output
                media. If there are problems with the topic source structure, they will show up
                here. </p>

            <p> The presentation stage also resolves subject-affinity links. Using the link catalogs
                created during the synthesis stage, <feature>soft links</feature> in source topics
                become actual links.</p>

            <p> The presentation stage produces an XML for each topic set with stage output for
                content in the file <code>
                content-set-id/build/topic-sets/&lt;topic-set-id&gt;/presentation-&lt;type&gt;/out/presentation.xml
                </code>. </p>

        </section>

        <section>
            <title>Formatting stage</title>

            <p> The formatting stage produces each content page in an XML representation of the
                output format. If the output format <italic>is</italic> XML, such as XHTML, then
                this will be the final stage.</p>

            <p> The formatting stage does not create its output in the build directory. Rather,
                output content is created in the directory <code>
                    $SPFE_BUILD_DIR/&lt;content-set-id&gt;/output </code>.</p>

        </section>

        <section>
            <title>Encoding stage</title>

            <p> If the output format is other than XML, such as PDF, then the XML produced in the
                formatting stage will be encoded here. </p>

        </section>

    </body>
</generic-topic>

