<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- This file is part of the SPFE Open Toolkit. See the accompanying license.txt file for applicable licenses.-->
<!-- (c) Copyright Analecta Communications Inc. 2012 All Rights Reserved. -->
<docset-home-topic xmlns="http://spfeopentoolkit.org/ns/spfe-docs"
    xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
    xsi:schemaLocation="http://spfeopentoolkit.org/ns/spfe-docs http://spfeopentoolkit.org/spfe-docs/topic-types/docset-home-topic/schemas/docset-home-topic.xsd">
    <head>
        <id>index</id>
        <history>
            <revision>
                <date>2012-04-22</date>
                <author>mbaker</author>
                <comment>New topic</comment>
                <status>In progress</status>
            </revision>
        </history>
        <index>
            <entry>
                <type>document-name</type>
                <term>SPFE Development</term>
            </entry>
        </index>
    </head>
    <body>
        <title>SPFE Open Toolkit Documentation</title>
        <p>The <string-ref id-ref="product"/> is a toolkit for building
            content creation systems using the <feature>SPFE architecture</feature>. </p>
        <p>The SPFE architecture is designed to facilitate the creation of structured writing
            systems that use a <feature>bottom-up architecture</feature>. A bottom up architecture
            is characterized by:</p>
        <ul>
            <li>
                <p><feature>Topics</feature> or pages are written on the <feature>Every Page is Page
                        One</feature> principle: Each page is a potential landing page and starting
                    point for the user, and there is no one preferred path through the content
                    set.</p>
            </li>
            <li>
                <p>Topics or pages are added to the collection individually, without the need to
                    place them in a top-down structure or <feature>table of contents</feature>. New
                    pages are integrated automatically into the collection based on their
                        <feature>metadata</feature>. Collections are formed by queries and all
                    topics that meet the conditions of the query are included automatically.</p>
            </li>
            <li>
                <p>Topics or pages work as hubs of their local semantic space, <task>linking to
                        topics on related subjects</task>. </p>
            </li>
        </ul>
        <p>Bottom-up architectures are common on the Web. Both wikis and blogging platforms, as well
            as many Web CMS work on the bottom-up pattern. However, there are no bottom-up systems
            based on markup-based structured writing principles (some database-based structured
            bottom-up systems exist). The <string-ref id-ref="product"/> is
            designed to fill this gap.</p>
        <p>The SPFE-OT is also capable of creating top-down and hybrid top-down/bottom-up
            architectures.</p>
        <p>Unlike the DocBook and DITA systems, SPFE is not based on a particular schema. Rather,
            SPFE is a modular content processing architecture that can be used with a variety of
            schemas. However, SPFE does make certain <feature>presumptions about how schemas will be
                written</feature>. In particular it expects a <feature>declarative style of
                markup</feature> in which the document markup does not contain any publishing or
            content management directives. </p>
        <p>To enable users to get up to speed quickly, and to provide a baseline of functionality
            for building SPFE-compatible schemas, <string-ref id-ref="product"
            /> includes the <feature>EPPO Simple schema set</feature>. EPPO Simple is a highly
            modularized set of schemas and associated processing that you can use directly or as the
            basis for <task>creating your own schemas</task>.</p>
    </body>
</docset-home-topic>
