<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- This file is part of the SPFE Open Toolkit. See the accompanying license.txt file for applicable licenses.-->
<!-- (c) Copyright Analecta Communications Inc. 2012 All Rights Reserved. -->

<essay xmlns="http://spfeopentoolkit.org/ns/spfe-docs"
    xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
    xsi:schemaLocation="http://spfeopentoolkit.org/ns/spfe-docs
    http://spfeopentoolkit.org/spfe-docs/topic-types/essay/schemas/authoring/essay.xsd">
 
    <head>
        <id>structured-content</id>
        <history>
            <revision>
                <date>2014-10-25</date>
                <author>jfmacdonald</author>
                <comment>New topic</comment>
                <status>In progress</status>
            </revision>
            <revision>
                <date>2014-11-30</date>
                <author>jfmacdonald</author>
                <comment>New topic</comment>
                <status>Ready for technical review</status>
            </revision>
            <revision>
                <date>2015-09-03</date>
                <author>mbaker</author>
                <comment>Converted to the essay schema</comment>
                <status>In progress</status>
            </revision>
        </history>
        <index>
            <entry>
                <type>feature</type>
                <term>structured content</term>
            </entry>
            <entry>
                <type>feature</type>
                <term>metadata</term>
            </entry>
            <entry>
                <type>feature</type>
                <term>markup</term>
            </entry>
        </index>
    </head>
    <body>
        <title>What is structured content?</title>
        <byline>
            <author-name>J. F. MacDonald</author-name>
        </byline>
        <precis>
            <p>Structured content adds metadata to content to serve a specific and limited purpose in an automated content creation and delivery system.</p>
        </precis>
        <p> Information is structured when its functional components are tagged with metadata
            such that computer programs may retain content structure and purpose when processing
            it.</p>


        <p> If you've written a letter, you've written <feature>structured content</feature>. If it was a
            formal letter, you likely wrote your name, return address, and date at the top, aligned
            on either the left or right side of the page, followed by the name and address of the
            person or institution for whom the letter was intended. After the salutation and body of
            the letter, you would have closed the letter with the appropriate farewell, your
            signature, name, and possibly your title. The letter followed a recognizable
            <italic>structure.</italic>   </p>

        <p> Correctly recognizing and interpreting such a letter requires a human reader familiar
            with the form and conventions of letters.  Increasingly in today's world, the content we
            create must first be interpreted, transmitted, transformed, and reformatted by computer
            software before a human sees it. For a human, a properly formatted letter is structured
            content, whether it is typed or handwritten. But for a computer, it is unstructured.
            Scan or fax the letter, and software sees only bits to encode, transmit, and decode. The
            software won't recognize it as a letter; it can only reproduce the image that was
            scanned.</p>

        <p> Here, we consider content to be structured if computer programs can recognize and retain
            its structure and purpose when processing it.</p> 

        <section>
            <title>Structured content is tagged with metadata</title>

        <p> For software to retain content structure while reformatting or otherwise processing it,
            the content must be tagged with <feature>metadata</feature>. Metadata is additional
            information that identifies the structural role that content components play.
            Information that identifies your letter's return address <italic>as</italic> a return
            address would be such metadata.  </p>

        <p> Many methods can and are used to tag content with metadata. The following are widely
            used:</p>

        <ul>
            <li><p><feature>XML</feature></p></li>
            <li><p><link-external href="http://www.w3.org/standards/webdesign/htmlcss">HTML</link-external></p></li>
            <li><p><link-external href="https://meta.wikimedia.org/wiki/Wiki_syntax">MediaWiki Wikitext</link-external></p></li>
            <li><p><link-external href="http://daringfireball.net/projects/markdown/">Markdown</link-external></p></li>
            <li><p><link-external href="http://tug.org/">TeX</link-external> and its derivative 
                   <link-external href="http://latex-project.org/">LaTeX</link-external></p></li>
        </ul>

        <p> But tagging information alone does not make it structured content. Content must
            <italic>function</italic> after it's processed by a computer program for it to serve its
            purpose.  Simply tagging your letter's destination address as right-aligned and bold
            will not guarentee it will reach it's destination.  A program must recognize the address
            as a destination address.</p>

        </section>
        
        <section>
            <title>Structured content functions as a whole to serve a purpose</title>

        <p> Information takes on meaning when it serves a purpose. An address found on a torn slip
            of paper could mean many things.  It could have been a letter's return or destination
            address. It could have been given to someone who needed directions.  It could have been
            torn from a tax return. You can assign the address's purpose and meaning only when you
            can place it in context.  To find context, you need additional information.  </p>

        <p> For a body of content to serve a purpose, it must contain sufficient information to
            identify that purpose. For structured content to function as a stand-alone unit of
            information, it must be not only be complete, but also have its intent captured in its
            metadata.  </p>

        <p> But metadata that does not serve the content's purpose is superfluous. It isn't
            necessary to know <italic>why</italic> a letter was written to deliver it. Structured
            content serves a specific and <italic>limited</italic> purpose.  </p>

        </section>
        
        <section>
            <title>Structured content conforms to a specific type</title>

        <p> To serve a specific purpose, structured content must conform to a specific
            <feature>type</feature>. That is, its <italic>structure</italic> must conform to a type.
            Whatever the content of a letter, it will function as a letter if it has the structure
            of a letter.  We can identify the letter with the type &quot;document,&quot; but that
            isn't sufficient to identify its purpose. We and our computer programs need more
            <feature>metadata</feature> than that.</p>

        <p> Content types can form a hierarchy. A letter is not only a letter but is also a
            document. For some purposes, such as where to store it on my personal computer, I may
            need only identify it as type &quot;document.&quot; But likely I'll store it in a folder
            that depends on the type of letter. I'll keep letters to loved ones and letters to the
            IRS in different folders. To identify that purpose, a structured letter would need to
            have metadata that identifies it not only as type &quot;letter,&quot; but also
            identifies the type of letter.</p>

        <p> As we can see in the case of a letter, an item of structured content may need to
            function in different ways. Thus its metadata needs to serve all its purposes. Yet we
            must identify one specific item of content with one specific type. Rather than encumber
            content typing with all the ways that an item of content may be used, we identify the
            content type with those essential features common for all its purposes. Whether we send
            it or file it away, a letter is a letter.</p>

        <p> So, some essential metadata identifies the content type, and optional metadata can
            further help the content fulfill its purpose.</p>

        </section>
        
        <section>
            <title>This document is an example of structured content</title>
            
            <p> Though this is a generic document, it has structure. Its structure is illustrated
                in the following <feature>structure diagram</feature>.</p>
            
            <fig>
                <title>EPPO-simple generic-topic structure</title>
                <caption>
                    <p> The tag <code>&lt;generic-topic&gt;</code> labels the <feature>root
                            element</feature> 
                        of a generic-topic document.</p>
                </caption>
                <graphic href="../../graphics/generic-topic.png"/>
            </fig>
            
            <p> The <feature>head</feature> element holds the document
                <feature>header</feature>, which
                comprises the <feature>identity</feature> group, the revision
                <feature>history</feature> group, and the <feature>index</feature> group. The latter
                contains the set of terms discussed in the topic. </p>
            
            <p> The <italic>body</italic> element holds the topic contents. A <feature>body-content
                </feature> group follows the main <italic>title</italic> element and every section
                title.</p>
  
            <p> Additional metadata is present in a <feature>header</feature> that helps process it in
                context of a larger body of content. The header metadata is intended for computer
                processing rather than for a human reader.</p>

            <p> This document has optional metadata that help it serve its purpose:</p>

            <ul>
                <li><p>Tags that identify sections</p></li>
                <li><p>Tags that identify external links</p></li>
                <li><p>Tags that identify terms that link to other topics in the content set</p></li>
                <li><p>Tags that annotate content for special formatting, such as italics</p></li>
            </ul>

            <p> As with a letter, a little metadata goes a long way in helping this content serve
                its purpose when it's processed by a computer. Or rather, <italic>preserve</italic>
                its purpose. It may or may not be a good letter or a good essay, but that's not the
                intent of structure metadata. The purpose of structure metadata is simply to
                preserve content's purpose when it's processed by computer programs.</p> 

        </section>
        
        <section>
            <title>Structured content serves both writers and readers</title>

        <p> Granted, we all know how to structure a letter. But a letter has many subtypes and
            purposes. You wouldn't write a love letter the same way you'd write a business letter.
            As evidenced by the number of how-to-write-a-letter books that have been published
            (<link-external href="http://www.amazon.com">amazon.com</link-external> lists more than
            a thousand), determining the form a specific letter should take is not a trivial task.
            As with creating most any kind of content, half the battle is in determining the
            structure that best serves its purpose.</p>

        <p> Information serves many purposes and many of those purposes, as those of a letter, are
            served with widely recognized structures.  Developing information types and defining
            content structures is both art and science. Writers who begin with a clearly defined
            purpose and develop or use structures that serves those purposes will have a better shot
            at achieving their purpose.  A reader may well have a different purpose. Yet, by
            preserving intent when it's distributed, structured content helps content users as well
            as authors. It helps users find what they need.  </p>

        </section>
        
    </body>
</essay>
