<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<essay xmlns="http://spfeopentoolkit.org/ns/spfe-docs"
    xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
    xsi:schemaLocation="http://spfeopentoolkit.org/ns/spfe-docs 
    http://spfeopentoolkit.org/spfe-docs/topic-types/essay/schemas/essay.xsd">
    
    <head>
        <id>how-does-xml-work</id>
        <history>
            <revision>
                <date>2014-10-26</date>
                <author>jfmacdonald</author>
                <comment>New topic</comment>
                <status>In progress</status>
            </revision>
            <revision>
                <date>2014-11-02</date>
                <author>jfmacdonald</author>
                <comment>Add index entries</comment>
                <status>In progress</status>
            </revision>
        </history>
        <index>
            <entry>
                <type>term</type>
                <term>XML</term>
            </entry>
            <entry>
                <type>term</type>
                <term>element</term>
            </entry>
            <entry>
                <type>term</type>
                <term>tag</term>
            </entry>
            <entry>
                <type>term</type>
                <term>markup</term>
            </entry>
            <entry>
                <type>term</type>
                <term>head</term>
            </entry>
            <entry>
                <type>term</type>
                <term>header</term>
            </entry>
            <entry>
                <type>term</type>
                <term>body</term>
            </entry>
        </index>
    </head>
    <body>
        <title>How does XML work?</title>
        <byline>
            <author-name>John Farrell MacDonald</author-name>
        </byline>
        
        <precis> 
            <p> Standardized by the World Wide Web Consortium (W3C), the
                Extensible Markup Language (XML) has a rich body of technologies
                and tools that support it. Though the SPFE architecture could be
                implemented in other ways, XML was selected because of its
                robust set of tools and the fact that it is an open
                standard.</p> 
        </precis>
        
        <p> The Extensible Markup Language (<term>XML</term>) is, as stated by
            its standardizing body, the <link-external
                href="http://www.w3.org/standards/xml/">World Wide Web
                Consortium (W3C)</link-external>, &quot;a simple text-based
            format for representing structured information.&quot; Because it is
            an open standard based on a rich history of markup formats and the
            work of many people, XML is widely used and is supported by a strong
            set of XML technlogies. The SPFE Open Toolkit is based on XML and
            its supporting technologies.</p>
        
        <section>
            <title>What is XML?</title>
            
            <p> The essense of the format is that textual information is placed
                within tagged containers called <term>elements</term>. This page,
                which was written using XML markup, begins with a snippet of XML
                like that below. </p>
            
            <codeblock><![CDATA[
    <title>How does XML work?</title>
    <byline>
        <author-name>John Farrell MacDonald</author-name>
    </byline>]]></codeblock>
        
            <subhead>Elements</subhead>
            
            <p> An element is a content container. An element begins with a tag,
                an identifying name enclosed in angle brackets, and ends with a
                matching tag, which preceeds the identifier with a slash. We
                speak loosely when referring to both opening and closing tags
                and everything inbetween as an <quote>element,</quote> but
                stricktly speaking, the element is just the container. We do
                take care not to call a tag an element or an element a tag.
                Think of a tag as a lid.</p>
                
            <p> In the snippet of XML above, <code>&lt;title&gt;</code> is
                an opening tag and <code>&lt;/title&gt;</code> is its closing
                tag. (We need a lid on both ends.) The title element holds
                a byline element, which holds an author-name element, which
                holds an author's name in simple text.</p>
                
            <p> Why the author-name element? It seems redundant; we could have
                placed the author's name directly in the byline element. But
                that would have presented a problem if there were more than one
                author. A simple comma may suffice for you and I to divide the
                text into a list of multiple authors, but we don't want to that
                task to a computer program. By placing each author's name in a
                separate element, we have created unambiguous markup.</p>
                
            <p> A tag associates <term>metadata</term> with its element's
                contents. A computer program with instructions for the tag
                can then process the element and its contents properly. In XML,
                metadata is not only information about contents but is also
                information that instructs a program what to do. A tag is not
                just a lid, it's a lid with an instructive label.</p>
                
            <subhead>The XML document element</subhead>
            
            <p> With elements containing other elements, among them there must be some
                that don't contain and some that are not contained. We call the
                elements within a containing element that element's <quote>children</quote>
                and call that element the contained element's parent. Thus, among them all,
                some are both children and parent, some are children only, and others are
                parents only.</p>
                
            <p> But a valid XML document can only have one parent. All elements in an
                XML file must derive from a single root element. We call the root
                element the <quote>document element.</quote></p>
                
            <subhead>Attributes</subhead>
            
            <p> Sometimes a tag needs some additional information to work
                properly. For example, the HTML <code>&lt;a&gt;</code> tag
                represents a hyperlink but needs extra information to provide a
                link address. That information can be given by adding an
                <term>attribute</term>. In the following, the <code>href</code>
                attribute is added to the <code>&lt;a&gt;</code> tag. </p>
            
            <codeblock><![CDATA[
    <a href="http://spfeopentoolkit.org/">The SPFE Open Toolkit</a>]]>
            </codeblock>
    
            <subhead>Other XML components</subhead>
            
            <p> Whereas elements do the primary work of an XML document, specialist
                need to be called in for some tasks. Along with elements, you'll
                often find the following other components in an XML document.</p>
                
            <ul>
                <li>
                    <p> <bold>Comments</bold> are for the benefit of human
                    readers. A comment is bracketed in the form <code>&lt;!-- a
                    comment --&gt;</code>. </p>
                
                </li>
                <li>
                    <p> <bold>Processing instructions</bold> provide a computer
                    program with instructions that don't pertain to any
                    particular element. A processing instruction has the form
                    <code>&lt;?keyword attributes ?&gt;</code>. You will
                    typically see a processing instruction at the top of an XML
                    file, which alerts a program that it is an XML file:
                    <![CDATA[<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>]]></p>
                </li>               
            </ul>
            
            <subhead>Where can I learn more?</subhead>
            
            <p>The W3C website provides a wealth of resources for learning more
                about XML and XML technologies. Liam R. E. Quin's article <link-external
                href="http://www.w3.org/standards/xml/core">XML Essentials</link-external>
                is a good place to start.</p>
                
        </section>
        
        <section>
            <title>What is a valid XML document?</title>
            
            <p> Though tagged elements imply meaning, a computer program can't
                interpret them properly unless it's coded to do so. Further, a
                program generally can't process an element correctly unless it
                comes upon the element in the proper context. For example, how
                should a program interpret the element &lt;title&gt;A
                Title&lt;/title&gt; placed in the midst of a paragraph, even
                though it were coded to recognize a title element?</p>
                
            <p> To avoid such ambiguity, an XML document needs to follow certain
                rules to be valid. These rules, called <quote>schemas,</quote>
                define which elements can go where and what they can contain.
                Thus a valid XML document has a defined <term>structure</term>.
                The SPFE Open Toolkit uses the <term>XML Schema</term>
                standardized by W3C. To be processed, every XML file the
                toolkit uses must be valid.</p>
                                
        </section>
        
        <section>
            <title>What XML document types does the SPFE Open Toolkit use?</title>
            <p> The toolkit works with two kinds of XML documents.</p>
            <ul>
                <li><p>content documents</p></li>
                <li><p>configuration documents</p></li>
            </ul>
            <p> Most of the XML documents you will work with when creating content
                are, of course, content documents. These all have a common basic
                structure: a root <term>document element</term> with two children,
                a <term>head</term> element and a <term>body</term> element. The
                example below shows the structure for the <feature>generic topic</feature>
                XML structure.</p>
                <codeblock>
<![CDATA[
<generic-topic>
    <head>
        <!-- Topic header goes here. It contains metadata about the document. -->
    </head>
    <body>
        <title>This is a title</title>
        <!-- The body goes here. It contains the actual content. -->
    </body>
</generic-topic>]]>
                </codeblock>
        </section>
             
        <section>
            <title>Who uses XML?</title>
            
            <p> Many methods can and are used to add metadata to content, but
                those that use XML to markup documents are the most widespread
                and robust. These include the following: </p>
            
            <ul>                
                <li> <p> The <link-external
                    href="http://dita.xml.org/standard">Darwin Information
                    Typing Architecture (DITA)</link-external>, which has been
                    standardized by the <link-external
                        href="https://www.oasis-open.org/">OASIS
                        consortium</link-external>, defines an XML markup
                    architecture for creating structured content.</p> </li>
                
                <li> <p> <link-external
                    href="http://www.docbook.org/">DocBook</link-external>
                    defines an XML markup for books and similarly structured
                    documents. Like DITA, an OASIS technical committee maintains
                    its standard.</p></li>
            </ul>
            
        </section>
        
    </body>
</essay>

