<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- This file is part of the SPFE Open Toolkit. See the accompanying license.txt file for applicable licenses.-->
<!-- (c) Copyright Analecta Communications Inc. 2015 All Rights Reserved. -->
<think-plan-do-topic xmlns="http://spfeopentoolkit.org/ns/spfe-docs" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://spfeopentoolkit.org/ns/spfe-docs
    http://spfeopentoolkit.org/spfe-docs/topic-types/think-plan-do-topic/schemas/authoring/think-plan-do-topic.xsd">
   <head>
       <id>task-table-of-contents</id>
       <history>
           <revision>
               <date>2015-08-26</date>
               <author>mbaker</author>
               <comment>New topic</comment>
               <status>In progress</status>
           </revision>
       </history>
       <index>
           <entry>
               <type>feature</type>
               <term>table of contents</term>
           </entry>
            <entry>
                <type>task</type>
                <term>create table of contents</term>
            </entry>
       </index>
   </head>
    <body>
        <title>Tables of Contents</title>
        <understanding>
            <p>Because SPFE is designed for <concept>bottom-up information architectures</concept>,
                a table of contents is considered a secondary navigation tool. However, most
                bottom-up information architectures should still have some form of table of
                contents. This is not necessarily a single hierarchical table that encompasses the
                entire <feature>content set</feature>. A typical arrangement might be to have one
                table of contents for the <feature>content set</feature>, and individual tables of
                contents for the <feature>topic sets</feature>. This is the default configuration
                for <feature>EPPO-simple</feature> and its derivatives. </p>
            <p>In EPPO-simple, and by default in topic types derived from it, a table of content for
                the <feature>content set</feature> is built automatically from the
                <feature>topic type groups</feature> define in the SPFE
                <feature>content set configuration file</feature>. Tables of contents for
                <feature>topic sets</feature> are built automatically by the
                <feature>toc build step</feature> according to the logic of the specified
                <feature>TOC script</feature>. The default TOC script groups the topics in a topic
                set by topic type and lists them in alphabetical order within the
                <feature>topic type groupings</feature>. The order in which topic types appear in a
                topic set TOC is determined by the order in which the <feature>topic types</feature>
                in a <feature>topic set</feature> are listed in the setting
                <config-setting>/topic-set/topic-types</config-setting>. </p>
        </understanding>
        <planning>
            <planning-question>
                <planning-question-title>Do you need to change the default TOC generation?</planning-question-title>
                <planning-question-body>
                    <p>If you are writing <concept>Every Page is Page One topics</concept>, you
                        probably don't need to change the default TOC generation. If you are
                        creating a topic set that is designed as a continuous narrative (like a
                        book) and need to create a TOC with a specified order of topics, you can
                        <task>specify the order in a TOC file</task>. </p>
                    <note>
                        <title>Pending feature</title>
                        <p>Specifying an arbitrary TOC is a pending feature. It is not currently
                            implemented.</p>
                    </note>
                </planning-question-body>
            </planning-question>
        </planning>
        <doing>
            <p>To configure the <feature>content set table of contents</feature>, use the
                <config-setting>/content-set/topic-set-groups</config-setting> setting. </p>
            <p>To configure the order of topic set types in a <feature>topic set TOC</feature>, use
                the setting <config-setting>/topic-set/topic-types</config-setting>. </p>
            <p>To specify a different way of auto-generating a content set TOC,
                <task specifically="create content set TOC script">write</task> and
                <task specifically="configure content set TOC script">configure</task> a new
                <feature>content set TOC script</feature> for your <feature>content set</feature>. </p>
            <p>To specify a different way of auto-generating a <feature>topic set TOC</feature>,
                write and configure a new <feature>topic set TOC script</feature> for your
                <feature>topic set</feature>.</p>
        </doing>
    </body>
</think-plan-do-topic>
