<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- This file is part of the SPFE Open Toolkit. See the accompanying license.txt file for applicable licenses.-->
<!-- (c) Copyright Analecta Communications Inc. 2012 All Rights Reserved. -->
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/css" href="../../style/authoring/spfe-docs.css"?>
<generic-topic xmlns="http://spfeopentoolkit.org/spfe-docs/schemas/authoring/generic-topic"
    xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
    xsi:schemaLocation="http://spfeopentoolkit.org/spfe-docs/schemas/authoring/generic-topic
http://spfeopentoolkit.org/spfe-docs/schemas/authoring/generic-topic.xsd">

    <head>
        <uri>http://spfeopentoolkit.org/spfe-docs/content/tasks/configuration-file-basics.xml</uri>
        <author>jkeffer</author>
        <status>In progress</status>
        <history>
            <revision>
                <date>2012-03-22</date>
                <author>jkeffer</author>
                <comment>New topic</comment>
                <new-status>Not started</new-status>
            </revision>
        </history>
        <index>
            <entry>
                <type>feature</type>
                <term>configuration file</term>
            </entry>
            <entry>
                <type>xpath</type>
                <term>/spfe</term>
            </entry>
        </index>
    </head>
    <body>
        <title>Configuration file basics</title>
   
        <p>The SPFE configuration file is the core of the SPFE
            <xfeature>build system</xfeature>. It defines the XML elements that
            specify the content to include in the documentation set and the scripts to generate the
            output. You can define a single configuration file for the documentation set; however,
            unless you have a very simple documentation set, it is usually best to divide the
            configuration elements into different files and use an
            <xml-element-name>include</xml-element-name> element to import other configuration
            files. This enables you to maximize reuse and modularity. The set of configuration files
            makes up the complete set of elements that the build system needs to build the
            documentation set.</p>
        <p>SPFE provides the <file-name>spfe-config.xsd</file-name> schema. You can define your own
            schema, which may include the spfe-config schema and you can add elements that are
            specific to your documentation set. Each configuration file used to build the
            documentation set must follow the same schema.</p>
        <p>Items that apply to the entire documentation set should be specified in the main
            configuration file (the file specified as a parameter when you run the <tool-name>spfe</tool-name>
            build tool). You can override the value of elements as needed in other configuration
            files.</p>
        <p>The following elements must be defined in the main configuration file: </p>
        <ul>
            <li>
                <p><xml-element-name>spfe</xml-element-name>: The root element of the configuration
                    file; each configuration file must specify this element</p>
            </li>
            <li>
                <p><xml-element-name>doc-set</xml-element-name>: If you use a <feature>documentation
                        set</feature>, you must define the elements here</p>
            </li>
            <li>
                <p/>
            </li>
        </ul>
        <p>The following elements are good candidates to specify in the main configuration file:</p>
        <ul>
            <li>
                <p><xml-element-name>topic-type-alias</xml-element-name>: If you want to specify a
                    user-friendly name for a topic schema and you have multiple topic sets for a topic schema, it is a good idea to define this element in the main configuration file.</p>
            </li>
        </ul>
    </body>
</generic-topic>
