<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- This file is part of the SPFE Open Toolkit. See the accompanying license.txt file for applicable licenses.-->
<!-- (c) Copyright Analecta Communications Inc. 2012 All Rights Reserved. -->
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/css" href="../../style/authoring/spfe-docs.css"?>
<generic-topic xmlns="http://spfeopentoolkit.org/spfe-docs/schemas/authoring/generic-topic"
    xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
    xsi:schemaLocation="http://spfeopentoolkit.org/spfe-docs/schemas/authoring/generic-topic
http://spfeopentoolkit.org/spfe-docs/schemas/authoring/generic-topic.xsd">

    <head>
        <uri>http://spfeopentoolkit.org/spfe-docs/content/tasks/configuration-file-overview.xml</uri>
        <author>jkeffer</author>
        <status>In progress</status>
        <history>
            <revision>
                <date>2012-03-22</date>
                <author>jkeffer</author>
                <comment>New topic</comment>
                <new-status>Not started</new-status>
            </revision>
            <revision>
                <date>2013-07-05</date>
                <author>jkeffer</author>
                <comment>Initial content</comment>
                <new-status>In progress</new-status>
            </revision>
            <revision>
                <date>2013-07-12</date>
                <author>jkeffer</author>
                <comment>Updates to content and structure</comment>
                <new-status>Ready for technical review</new-status>
            </revision>
        </history>
        <index>
            <entry>
                <type>feature</type>
                <term>{configuration file}</term>
            </entry>
            <entry>
                <type>xpath</type>
                <term>/spfe</term>
            </entry>
        </index>
    </head>
    <body>
        <title>Configuration file overview</title>
   
        <p>The contents of the SPFE configuration file determine the behaviour of the SPFE Toolkit
                <feature>build system</feature>. It defines the XML elements that specify the
            content to include in the documentation set and the scripts to process the content to
            generate the output. You can use a single configuration file for the documentation set;
            however, unless you have a very simple documentation set, you should divide the
            configuration elements into a main configuration file and separate configuration files
            for each topic set. To maximize reuse and modularity, you use an
            <xml-element-name>include</xml-element-name> element to import other configuration
            files. The set of configuration files makes up the complete set of elements that the
            build system needs to build the documentation set.</p>
        <p>SPFE provides the <file-name>spfe-config.xsd</file-name> configuration schema. You can
            define your own configuration schema, which can reuse the
                <file-name>spfe-config.xsd</file-name> schema and you can define additional elements
            that you need to build your documentation set. The configuration files combine to form
            the complete set of elements; therefore, each configuration file used to build the
            documentation set must follow the same configuration schema.</p>
        <p>You should define elements that apply to the entire documentation set in the main
            configuration file (the file specified as a parameter when you run the
                <tool-name>spfe</tool-name> build tool). You can override the value of elements as
            needed in other configuration files.</p>
        <p>The following elements must be defined in the main configuration file: </p>
        <ul>
            <li>
                <p><xml-element-name>/spfe</xml-element-name>: This is the root element of the
                    configuration file; each configuration file must define this element.</p>
            </li>
            <li>
                <p><xml-element-name>/spfe/doc-set</xml-element-name>: If you use a
                        <feature>documentation set</feature>, you must define the element here.</p>
            </li>
        </ul>
        <p>The following elements often apply to the entire documentation set and you should specify
            them in the main configuration file:</p>
        <ul>
            <li>
                <p><xml-element-name>/spfe/topic-type-aliases</xml-element-name>: If you want to use
                    a user-friendly name for a topic set in the table of contents, and you have
                    multiple topic sets that use the same topic schema, define this element in the
                    main configuration file. The value of the
                    /<xml-attribute-name>spfe/topic-aliases/topic-type/@alias</xml-attribute-name>
                    attribute appears in the table of contents for the documentation set.</p>
            </li>
            <li>
                <p><xml-element-name>/spfe/wip-site</xml-element-name>: If you want to make a
                    documentation set under development available for internal viewing, define the
                    appropriate child elements for your test site. You need to modify the synthesis
                    scripts to use this feature of the SPFE Toolkit.</p>
            </li>
            <li>
                <p><xml-element-name>/spfe/scripts</xml-element-name> and
                    <xml-element-name>/spfe/sources</xml-element-name>: To avoid duplication, if one
                    or more topic sets use the same scripts or the same content, define these
                    elements in the main configuration file.</p>
            </li>
            <li>
                <p><xml-element-name>/spfe/output-formats</xml-element-name>: Define this element in
                    the main configuration file if all topic sets support at least one common output
                    format. Topic set configuration files can also define this element to add
                    additional output formats.</p>
            </li>
            <li>
                <p><xml-element-name>/spfe/style/html-output-directories</xml-element-name>: The
                    style sheets to format HTML output. There should be an overall style sheet and
                    individual topic sets can define this element to add additional style
                    sheets.</p>
            </li>
            <li>
                <p><xml-element-name>/spfe/messages</xml-element-name>: The message types the build
                    system generates. You usually want the to view the same message type for all
                    stages of the build. If you use the  SPFE Toolkit in an automated build system,
                    you can parse the SPFE output logs for build status information.</p>
            </li>
        </ul>
    </body>
</generic-topic>
