<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<think-plan-do-topic xmlns="http://spfeopentoolkit.org/ns/spfe-docs"
    xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
    xsi:schemaLocation="http://spfeopentoolkit.org/ns/spfe-docs 
    http://spfeopentoolkit.org/spfe-docs/topic-types/think-plan-do-topic/schemas/think-plan-do-topic.xsd">

    <head>
        <id>creating-a-topic</id>
        <history>
            <revision>
                <date>2014-10-30</date>
                <author>jfmacdonald</author>
                <comment>New topic</comment>
                <status>In progress</status>
            </revision>
            <revision>
                <date>2014-11-30</date>
                <author>jfmacdonald</author>
                <comment>New topic</comment>
                <status>Ready for technical review</status>
            </revision>
        </history>
        <index>
            <entry>
                <type>feature</type>
                <term>topic</term>
            </entry>
            <entry>
                <type>feature</type>
                <term>topic type</term>
            </entry>
            <entry>
                <type>feature</type>
                <term>EPPO simple</term>
            </entry>
        </index>
    </head>
    <body>
        <title>Creating a topic</title>
        <understanding>

            <p> In common usage, the term <italic>topic</italic> refers to the subject of a work.
                Here, we apply the term to a particular work -- a unit of content -- about a
                particular subject. Using the <feature> SPFE Open Toolkit </feature>, a
                topic is an XML document in the structure of a specific <feature> topic type
            </feature>. </p>

            <p> To be in the output of a <feature> content set </feature> build, a topic must be
                included in a <feature> topic set </feature> sources list (configuration setting
                <config-setting>/topic-set/sources</config-setting>). </p> 

        </understanding>
        <planning>

            <p> Before creating the document for a topic, consider the document's purpose and 
                select the <feature> topic type </feature> that best suits it. </p>

            <p> The <feature> SPFE Open Toolkit</feature> provides a set of topic types that may be
                used as a base for extended topic types in a particular deployment of the toolkit.
                These base types, called <feature>EPPO simple</feature>, include the following: </p>

            <ul> 

                <li> <p> <feature>docset-home topic</feature> </p> </li>

                <li> <p> <feature>essay</feature> </p> </li>

                <li> <p> <feature>feature topic</feature> </p> </li>

                <li> <p> <feature>generic topic</feature> </p> </li>

                <li> <p> <feature>think-plan-do topic</feature> </p> </li>

            </ul>

            <p> Of these, the <feature>generic topic</feature> is most general and forms a base
                for the others. </p>

        </planning>
        <doing>

            <subhead>Select an editor</subhead>

            <p> Create an XML file using editing software of your choice. Do not use a word
                processing program such as Microsoft Word. The editor must save output in plain
                text format.</p>

            <p> Several editors provide aids, such as syntax highlighting and schema validation, for
                editing XML markup.  Some cost and some are free. Features and support for XML vary.
                A short list includes the following: </p>

            <ul>

                <li> <p> <link-external href="http://www.oxygenxml.com/">Oxygen XML</link-external>
                        is a full-featured XML editor with schema support. In addition to direct
                        text editing, the software provides an "Author" editor that may be easier
                        for those more comfortable in a word-processing environment.  The software
                        must be purchased, but is less expensive than most other full-featured XML
                        editors. </p> </li>

                <li> <p> <link-external href="http://komodoide.com/komodo-edit/">Komodo Edit
                        </link-external> is a free editor with reasonable support for XML and
                        several other code formats. In addition to syntax support, the editor
                        verifies compliance with XML Schemas. </p> </li>

            </ul>

            <p> The above list is by no means comprehensive. You may likely find another editor more
                suitable. Often, the editor that works best is not that with the most features, but
                is the software you are most practiced and comfortable using. Finger habits are not
                easily relearned. </p>

            <subhead>Follow the topic type schema</subhead>

            <p> Review the <feature> structure diagram </feature> or other specification for the
                <feature> topic type </feature>. </p> 

            <subhead>Example</subhead>

            <fragment-ref id-ref="generic-topic-example" />

        </doing>
    </body>
</think-plan-do-topic>
