<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<element-descriptions
    xmlns="http://spfeopentoolkit.org/spfe-ot/plugins/config-schema-docs/schemas/element-descriptions"
    xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
    xsi:schemaLocation="http://spfeopentoolkit.org/spfe-ot/plugins/config-schema-docs/schemas/element-descriptions  http://spfeopentoolkit.org/spfe-ot/plugins/config-schema-docs/schemas/authoring/element-descriptions.xsd">
    <head>
        <base-uri>http://spfeopentoolkit.org/spfe-ot/plugins/config-schema-docs</base-uri>
        <name>element-descriptions</name>
        <author>Mark Baker</author>
        <status>In progress</status>
        <history>
            <revision>
                <date>2012-04-04</date>
                <author>Mark Baker</author>
                <comment>new</comment>
                <new-status>In progress</new-status>
            </revision>
        </history>
    </head>
    <schema-namespace>http://spfeopentoolkit.org/spfe-ot/1.0/schemas/spfe-config</schema-namespace>
    <element-description>
        <xpath>/spfe</xpath>
        <description>
            <p>The <xml-element-name>spfe</xml-element-name> element is the root element of a SPFE
                configuration file.</p>
            <p>You can spread your configuration over multiple configuration files. Each file must
                have a <xml-element-name>spfe</xml-element-name> root element. The
                    <tool-name>spfe</tool-name> command requires a spfe configuration file as a
                parameter. This is the configuration file that defines the properties for an
                individual build. It may include more general property files that are shared by
                multiple builds. You include other spfe configuration files using the
                <xml-element-name>/spfe/include</xml-element-name> element.</p>
        </description>
        <build-property/>
        <include-behavior/>
    </element-description>
    <element-description>
        <xpath>/spfe/include</xpath>
        <description>
            <p>The <xml-element-name>include</xml-element-name> element is used to include other
                SPFE configuraiton files in the current configuration file. Depending on the include
                behavior for each element, the elements in the current file will either be added to
                the elements in the included file or will replace the elements in the included file.
                See the <bold>Include Behavior</bold> section of each entry in this reference to see
                how each element is handled.</p>

        </description>
        <build-property/>
        <include-behavior>
            <p>When an included file is read, any includes in that file are read as well. Be careful
                not to create circular includes.</p>
        </include-behavior>
        <attributes>
            <attribute>
                <name>href</name>
                <description>
                    <p>The URL of the file to load. Note that XML Catalogs are not use to resolve
                        this URL. To ensure portability of your configuration file, either use a
                        relative URL or use <xml-element-name>/spfe/define</xml-element-name> to
                        create a constant for the root of the file path.</p>
                </description>
            </attribute>
        </attributes>
    </element-description>
    <element-description>
        <xpath>/spfe/define</xpath>
        <description>
            <p>The <xml-element-name>define</xml-element-name> element is used to define string
                constants that can be used to define other properites. </p>
            <p>To use a defined value in setting another property you surround the property name
                with <code>${</code> and <code>}</code>, as in the use of the <code>HOME</code>
                constant in the example above. The variables <code>HOME</code> (the user's home
                directory) and <code>SPFEOT_HOME</code> (the location of the SPFE Open Toolkit) are
                predefined. (<code>HOME</code> is taken from the operating system, and
                <code>SPFTOT_HOME</code> must be set as an environment variable when you
                    <task>install the SPFE Open Toolkit</task>).</p>
            <p>You can use one constant to define the value of another constant. The build tools
                will raise and error if a cercular definition is found. (That is, don't define A
                using B and then try to define B using A.)</p>
        </description>
        <build-property/>
        <include-behavior>
            <p>Definitions from included files are added to the definitions in the current file and
                the combined set of definitions is used in expanding constants in the property
                definitions in all files. (In other words, there it makes no difference where a
                particular constant is defined.)</p>
            <p>A definition in the current file with the same name as a definition in an included
                file overrides the definition from an included file.</p>
        </include-behavior>
        <attributes>
            <attribute>
                <name>name</name>
                <description>
                    <p>The name of the constant you are defining. The name must conform to the XML
                        NCName type. In practice, for visibility, it should consist of upper case
                        letters and underscores, with no spaces.</p>
                </description>
            </attribute>
            <attribute>
                <name>value</name>
                <description>
                    <p>The value of the constant. This can be anything you like, and you may include
                        other constants in the value of the constant you are defining, as long as
                        you do not create a circular definition. The value will be substituted for
                        the constant wherever it occurs as a straight string substitution.</p>
                </description>
            </attribute>
        </attributes>
    </element-description>
    <element-description>
        <xpath>/spfe/topic-set-id</xpath>
        <description>
            <p>The <xml-element-name>topic-set-id</xml-element-name> element specifies the
                identifier for the current <feature>topic set</feature>. This identifier can be used
                to create a reference to the topic set. It is also used to create file and directory
                names, so it should be a value that is a valid file name (minus extension) on all
                target systems.</p>
        </description>
        <build-property>spfe.topic-set-id</build-property>
        <include-behavior>
            <p>The value in the current file takes precedence over the value in the included
                file.</p>
        </include-behavior>
    </element-description>
    <element-description>
        <xpath>/spfe/publication-info</xpath>
        <description>
            <p>The <xml-element-name>publication-info</xml-element-name> element is a wrapper for
                the settings that define the publication information for a <feature>topic
                    set</feature>.</p>
        </description>
        <build-property/>
        <include-behavior>
            <p>The sub-elements in the current file individually take precedence over the same
                subelement in an included file. This means that you cannot override the entire
                <xml-element-name>publication-info</xml-element-name> element in the current file,
                only the individual sub files. This behavior is useful, for example, in situations
                where a sub-product has a different release number from other products in a
                documentation set. Shared publication information, including the release number, can
                be set in a shared file, and then overriden for products with a different release
                number.</p>
        </include-behavior>
    </element-description>
    <element-description>
        <xpath>/spfe/publication-info/product</xpath>
        <description>
            <p>The name of the product that the <feature>topic set</feature> describes.</p>
        </description>
        <build-property>spfe.publication-info.product</build-property>
        <include-behavior>
            <p>The value from the top-level configuration file takes precedence over the same
                setting in included configuration files.</p>
        </include-behavior>
    </element-description>
    <element-description>
        <xpath>/spfe/publication-info/title</xpath>
        <description>
            <p>The title of the <feature>topic set</feature>.</p>
        </description>
        <build-property>spfe.publication-info.product</build-property>
        <include-behavior>
            <p>The value from the top-level configuration file takes precedence over the same
                setting in included configuration files.</p>
        </include-behavior>
    </element-description>
    <element-description>
        <xpath>/spfe/publication-info/release</xpath>
        <description>
            <p>The release number of the product that the <feature>topic set</feature>
                describes.</p>
        </description>
        <build-property>spfe.publication-info.product</build-property>
        <include-behavior>
            <p>The value from the top-level configuration file takes precedence over the same
                setting in included configuration files.</p>
        </include-behavior>
    </element-description>
    <element-description>
        <xpath>/spfe/publication-info/copyright</xpath>
        <description>
            <p>The name of the product that the topic set describes.</p>
        </description>
        <build-property>spfe.publication-info.product</build-property>
        <include-behavior>
            <p>The value from the top-level configuration file takes precedence over the same
                setting in included configuration files.</p>
        </include-behavior>
    </element-description>
    <element-description>
        <xpath>/spfe/publication-info/other</xpath>
        <description>
            <p>The <xml-element-name>other</xml-element-name> element is used to create additional
                publication information fields if you have need for additional fields. You use the
                <xml-attribute-name>name</xml-attribute-name> attribute to specify a name for the
                additional configuration setting.</p>
        </description>
        <build-property>spfe.publication-info.other.{name}</build-property>
        <include-behavior>
            <p>All other elements from all included files are added to any other elements defined in
                the current configuration file, including those with the overlapping name values. In
                the generated build file, this will result in multiple properties with the same
                name, and per ANT's rules, the value of the first defined property will be used and
                the others will be ignored. In the generated configuration file that is passed to
                the build scripts, the duplicate other settings will be present. You can select the
                one from the top-level configuration file using a predicate of <code>[1]</code> on
                the xpath that selects this setting.</p>
        </include-behavior>
        <attributes>
            <attribute>
                <name>name</name>
                <description>
                    <p>The name of the other publication information field.</p>
                </description>
            </attribute>
        </attributes>
    </element-description>
    <element-description>
        <xpath>/spfe/topic-type-order</xpath>
        <description>
            <p>The order in which topic types are listed in the TOC if <feature>topic type
                    ordering</feature> is used.</p>
        </description>
        <build-property/>
        <include-behavior>
            <p>The value in the current configuration file overrides values in any included
                configuration files.</p>
        </include-behavior>
    </element-description>
    <element-description>
        <xpath>/spfe/sources</xpath>
        <description>
            <p>A container element for settings that point to various source files used in the
                build.</p>
        </description>
        <build-property/>
        <include-behavior>
            <p>The sub-elements in the current file individually take precedence over the same
                subelement in an included file. This means that you cannot override the entire
                <xml-element-name>sources</xml-element-name> element in the current file, only the
                individual sub files.</p>
        </include-behavior>
    </element-description>
    
    <element-description>
        <xpath>/spfe/sources/topics</xpath>
        <description>
            <p>A container element for a list of file selectors that select the topic files to be
                included in the build. Becomes an ANT fileset expression in the build file.</p>
        </description>
        <build-property>topics</build-property>
        <include-behavior>
            <p>The set of file selectors from included configuration files are added to the file
                selectors in the current configuration file.</p>
        </include-behavior>
    </element-description>
    
    <element-description>
        <xpath>/spfe/sources/topics/include</xpath>
        <description>
            <p>A path expression indicating topic files to include in the build. You can use wild cards. This path expression is used to create an <xml-element-name>include</xml-element-name> element in an ANT <xml-element-name>files</xml-element-name> element that is used to copy topic files to the build diretory for inclusion in the build.</p>
        </description>
        <build-property></build-property>
        <include-behavior>
            <p>The set of file selectors from included configuration files are added to the file
                selectors in the current configuration file.</p>
        </include-behavior>
    </element-description>
    

    <element-description>
        <xpath>/spfe/sources/text-objects</xpath>
        <description>
            <p>A container element for a list of file selectors that select the text-object files to be
                included in the build. Becomes an ANT fileset expression in the build file.</p>
        </description>
        <build-property>text-objects</build-property>
        <include-behavior>
            <p>The set of file selectors from included configuration files are added to the file
                selectors in the current configuration file.</p>
        </include-behavior>
    </element-description>

    <element-description>
        <xpath>/spfe/sources/text-objects/include</xpath>
        <description>
            <p>A path expression indicating <feature>text object</feature> files to include in the build. You can use wild cards. This path expression is used to create an <xml-element-name>include</xml-element-name> element in an ANT <xml-element-name>files</xml-element-name> element that is used to copy text object files to the build diretory for inclusion in the build.</p>
        </description>
        <build-property></build-property>
        <include-behavior>
            <p>The set of file selectors from included configuration files are added to the file
                selectors in the current configuration file.</p>
        </include-behavior>
    </element-description>

    <element-description>
        <xpath>/spfe/sources/fragments</xpath>
        <description>
            <p>A container element for a list of file selectors that select the fragment files to be
                included in the build. Becomes an ANT fileset expression in the build file.</p>
        </description>
        <build-property>fragments</build-property>
        <include-behavior>
            <p>The set of file selectors from included configuration files are added to the file
                selectors in the current configuration file.</p>
        </include-behavior>
    </element-description>

    <element-description>
        <xpath>/spfe/sources/fragments/include</xpath>
        <description>
            <p>A path expression indicating fragment files to include in the build. You can use wild cards. This path expression is used to create an <xml-element-name>include</xml-element-name> element in an ANT <xml-element-name>files</xml-element-name> element that is used to copy fragment files to the build diretory for inclusion in the build.</p>
        </description>
        <build-property></build-property>
        <include-behavior>
            <p>The set of file selectors from included configuration files are added to the file
                selectors in the current configuration file.</p>
        </include-behavior>
    </element-description>

    <element-description>
        <xpath>/spfe/sources/images</xpath>
        <description>
            <p>Specifies the location of images that can be used in the build. Note that only the images acrually reference in the text (either via hard linking or soft linking) will be inclued in the build itself. This setting just tells the build where to look for images.</p>
        </description>
        <build-property>spfe.directories.image-source</build-property>
        <include-behavior>
            <p>The definition in the current file takes precedence over definitions in included files.</p>
        </include-behavior>
    </element-description>
    
    <element-description>
        <xpath>/spfe/sources/graphics</xpath>
        <description>
            <p>A container element for a list of file selectors that select the graphics files to be
                included in the build. Becomes an ANT fileset expression in the build file.</p>
        </description>
        <build-property>graphics</build-property>
        <include-behavior>
            <p>The set of file selectors from included configuration files are added to the file
                selectors in the current configuration file.</p>
        </include-behavior>
    </element-description>

    <element-description>
        <xpath>/spfe/sources/graphics/include</xpath>
        <description>
            <p>A path expression indicating graphics files to include in the build. You can use wild cards. This path expression is used to create an <xml-element-name>include</xml-element-name> element in an ANT <xml-element-name>files</xml-element-name> element that is used to copy graphics files to the build diretory for inclusion in the build.</p>
        </description>
        <build-property></build-property>
        <include-behavior>
            <p>The set of file selectors from included configuration files are added to the file
                selectors in the current configuration file.</p>
        </include-behavior>
    </element-description>

    <element-description>
        <xpath>/spfe/sources/graphics-catalog</xpath>
        <description>
            <p>A container element for a list of file selectors that select the graphics-catalog files to be
                included in the build. Becomes an ANT fileset expression in the build file.</p>
        </description>
        <build-property>graphics-catalog</build-property>
        <include-behavior>
            <p>The set of file selectors from included configuration files are added to the file
                selectors in the current configuration file.</p>
        </include-behavior>
    </element-description>

    <element-description>
        <xpath>/spfe/sources/graphics-catalog/include</xpath>
        <description>
            <p>A path expression indicating <feature>graphics catalog</feature> files to include in the build. You can use wild cards. This path expression is used to create an <xml-element-name>include</xml-element-name> element in an ANT <xml-element-name>files</xml-element-name> element that is used to copy <feature>graphics catalog</feature> files to the build diretory for inclusion in the build.</p>
        </description>
        <build-property></build-property>
        <include-behavior>
            <p>The set of file selectors from included configuration files are added to the file
                selectors in the current configuration file.</p>
        </include-behavior>
    </element-description>

    <element-description>
        <xpath>/spfe/sources/strings</xpath>
        <description>
            <p>A container element for a list of file selectors that select the strings files to be
                included in the build. Becomes an ANT fileset expression in the build file.</p>
        </description>
        <build-property>strings</build-property>
        <include-behavior>
            <p>The set of file selectors from included configuration files are added to the file
                selectors in the current configuration file.</p>
        </include-behavior>
    </element-description>

    <element-description>
        <xpath>/spfe/sources/strings/include</xpath>
        <description>
            <p>A path expression indicating <feature>strings</feature> files to include in the build. You can use wild cards. This path expression is used to create an <xml-element-name>include</xml-element-name> element in an ANT <xml-element-name>files</xml-element-name> element that is used to copy <feature>strings</feature> files to the build diretory for inclusion in the build.</p>
        </description>
        <build-property></build-property>
        <include-behavior>
            <p>The set of file selectors from included configuration files are added to the file
                selectors in the current configuration file.</p>
        </include-behavior>
    </element-description>
    
    <element-description>
        <xpath>/spfe/sources/link-catalogs</xpath>
        <description>
            <p>A container element for a list of file selectors that select the link-catalog files to be
                used for linking topics. The setting becomes an ANT fileset expression in the build file.</p>
            <p>The link catalogs for the current topic set will be created in the location specified by <xml-element-name>/spfe/build/link-catalog-directory</xml-element-name>. Make sure that the path specified by <xml-element-name>spfe/build/link-catalog-directory</xml-element-name> is included in those specified by <xml-element-name>/spfe/sources/link-catalogs</xml-element-name>.</p>
            <p>You can also include link catalogs for other topic sets in the documentation set, or link catalogs from other documentation sets, in the list of link catalogs used to link the current topic set. The simplest way to have the entire documentation set use the same link catalogs is to set <xml-element-name>/spfe/sources/link-catalogs</xml-element-name> and <xml-element-name>spfe/build/link-catalog-directory</xml-element-name> to the same directory, and to define them both in the  shared configuration file for the documentation set.</p>
        </description>
        <build-property>link-catalogs</build-property>
        <include-behavior>
            <p>The set of file selectors from included configuration files are added to the file
                selectors in the current configuration file.</p>
        </include-behavior>
    </element-description>

    <element-description>
        <xpath>/spfe/sources/link-catalogs/include</xpath>
        <description>
            <p>A path expression indicating <feature>link catalog</feature> files to include in the build. You can use wild cards. This path expression is used to create an <xml-element-name>include</xml-element-name> element in an ANT <xml-element-name>files</xml-element-name> element that is used to copy <feature>link catalog</feature> files to the build diretory for inclusion in the build.</p>
        </description>
        <build-property></build-property>
        <include-behavior>
            <p>The set of file selectors from included configuration files are added to the file
                selectors in the current configuration file.</p>
        </include-behavior>
    </element-description>

    <element-description>
        <xpath>/spfe/sources/synonyms</xpath>
        <description>
            <p>A container element for a list of file selectors that select the synonyms files to be
                included in the build. Becomes an ANT fileset expression in the build file.</p>
        </description>
        <build-property>synonyms</build-property>
        <include-behavior>
            <p>The set of file selectors from included configuration files are added to the file
                selectors in the current configuration file.</p>
        </include-behavior>
    </element-description>

    <element-description>
        <xpath>/spfe/sources/synonyms/include</xpath>
        <description>
            <p>A path expression indicating <feature>synonyms</feature> files to include in the build. You can use wild cards. This path expression is used to create an <xml-element-name>include</xml-element-name> element in an ANT <xml-element-name>files</xml-element-name> element that is used to copy <feature>synonyms</feature> files to the build diretory for inclusion in the build.</p>
        </description>
        <build-property></build-property>
        <include-behavior>
            <p>The set of file selectors from included configuration files are added to the file
                selectors in the current configuration file.</p>
        </include-behavior>
    </element-description>

    <element-description>
        <xpath>/spfe/sources/other</xpath>
        <description>
            <p>A container element for a list of file selectors that select other files to be
                included in the build. The name of the the set of files is specified by the <xml-attribute-name>name</xml-attribute-name> attribute. Becomes an ANT fileset expression in the build file.</p>
        </description>
        <build-property>other.{name}</build-property>
        <include-behavior>
            <p>The set of file selectors from included configuration files are added to the file
                selectors in the current configuration file.</p>
        </include-behavior>
        <attributes>
            <attribute>
                <name>name</name>
                <description>
                    <p>The name of the type of other source.</p>
                </description>
            </attribute>
        </attributes>
    </element-description>
    
    <element-description>
        <xpath>/spfe/sources/other/include</xpath>
        <description>
            <p>A path expression indicating other files to include in the build. You can use wild cards. This path expression is used to create an <xml-element-name>include</xml-element-name> element in an ANT <xml-element-name>files</xml-element-name> element that is used to copy other files to the build diretory for inclusion in the build.</p>
        </description>
        <build-property></build-property>
        <include-behavior>
            <p>The set of file selectors from included configuration files are added to the file
                selectors in the current configuration file.</p>
        </include-behavior>
    </element-description>

    <element-description>
        <xpath>/spfe/condition-tokens</xpath>
        <description>
            <p>The <xml-element-name>conditions-token</xml-element-name> element specifies the <feature>condition tokens</feature> that will be applied to the build.</p>
        </description>
        <build-property></build-property>
        <include-behavior>
            <p>The value from the current config file overrides the values in included files.</p>
        </include-behavior>
    </element-description>
    
    <element-description>
        <xpath>/spfe/default-topic-scope</xpath>
        <description>
            <p>Specifies the <feature>topic scope</feature> tokens to be applied to all topics in the build by default. Effectively, specifying this setting applies scope to topics that do not specify a scope. Topics that declare their own scope are not affected by this setting.</p>
        </description>
        <build-property></build-property>
        <include-behavior>
            <p>The value from the current config file overrides the values in included files.</p>
        </include-behavior>
    </element-description>
    
    <element-description>
        <xpath>/spfe/default-mention-scope</xpath>
        <description>
            <p>Specifies the <feature>mention scope</feature> tokens to be applied to all mentions in all topics in the build by default. Effectively, specifying this setting applies scope to mentions that do not specify a scope. Mentions that declare their own scope are not affected by this setting.</p>
        </description>
        <build-property></build-property>
        <include-behavior>
            <p>The value from the current config file overrides the values in included files.</p>
        </include-behavior>
    </element-description>
    
    <element-description>
        <xpath>/spfe/output-formats</xpath>
        <description>
            <p>Specifies the output formats to be created.</p>
        </description>
        <build-property></build-property>
        <include-behavior>
            <p>The value from the current config file overrides the values in included files.</p>
        </include-behavior>
    </element-description>
    
    <element-description>
        <xpath>/spfe/topic-type-aliases</xpath>
        <description>
            <p>Topic types in SPFE are identified by the namespace identifier of the topic schema. In some cases, however, we need to display the topic type to the user. For this purpose we need a user-friendly alias for the topic type. The <xml-element-name>topic-type-aliases</xml-element-name> element is a container for a list of topic type aliases that the build tools can use to display a user-friendly name for a topic type.</p>
        </description>
        <build-property></build-property>
        <include-behavior>
            <p>Items in the topic types alias list from the current and all included configuration files are combined into a single list. In the event that the same topic type is listed more than once, the first definition in the configuration file highest in the include sequence will be used.</p>
        </include-behavior>
    </element-description>
    
    <element-description>
        <xpath>/spfe/topic-type-aliases/topic-type</xpath>
        <description>
            <p>Contains an item in the <feature>topic type alias</feature> list.</p>
        </description>
        <build-property></build-property>
        <include-behavior></include-behavior>
    </element-description>
    
    <element-description>
        <xpath>/spfe/topic-type-aliases/topic-type/id</xpath>
        <description>
            <p>The topic type id, that is, the namespace identifier of the topic type schema.</p>
        </description>
        <build-property></build-property>
        <include-behavior></include-behavior>
    </element-description>
    
    <element-description>
        <xpath>/spfe/topic-type-aliases/topic-type/alias</xpath>
        <description>
            <p>The alias for the topic type <xml-element-name xpath="/spfe/topic-type-aliases/topic-type/id">id</xml-element-name>, that is, a reader-friendly name for the topic type.</p>
        </description>
        <build-property></build-property>
        <include-behavior></include-behavior>
    </element-description>
    
    <element-description>
        <xpath>/spfe/topic-type-aliases/topic-type/plural</xpath>
        <description>
            <p>The plural version of the <xml-element-name xpath="/spfe/topic-type-aliases/topic-type/alias">alias</xml-element-name> for the topic type <xml-element-name xpath="/spfe/topic-type-aliases/topic-type/id">id</xml-element-name>.</p>
        </description>
        <build-property></build-property>
        <include-behavior></include-behavior>
    </element-description>
    
    <element-description>
        <xpath>/spfe/messages</xpath>
        <description>
            <p>Specifies the types of messages that will be generated by the build. Possible value are <code>info</code>, and <code>warning</code>.</p>
        </description>
        <build-property>spfe.message-types</build-property>
        <include-behavior>
            <p>The definition in the current file takes precedence over definitions in included files.</p>
        </include-behavior>
    </element-description>
    
    <element-description>
        <xpath>/spfe/wip-site</xpath>
        <description>
            <p>A container element for configuration information on the <feature>work in porgress site</feature>.</p>
        </description>
        <build-property></build-property>
        <include-behavior>
            <p>TBD</p>
        </include-behavior>
    </element-description>
    
    <element-description>
        <xpath>/spfe/wip-site/href</xpath>
        <description>
            <p>The href of the <feature>work in progress site</feature>.</p>
        </description>
        <build-property>spfe.wip-site.href</build-property>
        <include-behavior></include-behavior>
    </element-description>
    
    <element-description>
        <xpath>/spfe/wip-site/ftp</xpath>
        <description>
            <p>A container for login information for FTP access to the <feature>work in progress site</feature>.</p>
        </description>
        <build-property></build-property>
        <include-behavior></include-behavior>
    </element-description>
    
    <element-description>
        <xpath>/spfe/wip-site/ftp/url</xpath>
        <description>
            <p>The URL of the ftp login to the <feature>work in progress site</feature>.</p>
        </description>
        <build-property>spfe.wip-site.ftp.url</build-property>
        <include-behavior></include-behavior>
    </element-description>
    
    <element-description>
        <xpath>/spfe/wip-site/ftp/user</xpath>
        <description>
            <p>The user name for loging in to the <feature>work in progress site</feature>.</p>
        </description>
        <build-property>spfe.wip-site.ftp.user</build-property>
        <include-behavior></include-behavior>
    </element-description>
    
    <element-description>
        <xpath>/spfe/wip-site/ftp/password</xpath>
        <description><p>The ftp password for the <feature>work in progress site</feature>.</p></description>
        <build-property>spfe.wip-site.ftp.password</build-property>
        <include-behavior></include-behavior>
    </element-description>
    
    
    <element-description>
        <xpath>/spfe/wip-site/path</xpath>
        <description>
            <p>The file path to the root of the <feature>work in progress site</feature>.</p>
        </description>
        <build-property>spfe.wip-site.path</build-property>
        <include-behavior></include-behavior>
    </element-description>
    
    <element-description>
        <xpath>/spfe/build</xpath>
        <description>
            <p>A container element for settings related to the build environment.</p>
        </description>
        <build-property></build-property>
        <include-behavior></include-behavior>
    </element-description>
    
    <element-description>
        <xpath>/spfe/build/output-directory</xpath>
        <description>
            <p>Specifies the directory where the build output will be created.</p>
        </description>
        <build-property>spfe.directories.output</build-property>
        <include-behavior>            
            <p>The definition in the current file takes precedence over definitions in included files.</p>
        </include-behavior>
    </element-description>
    
    <element-description>
        <xpath>/spfe/build/link-catalog-directory</xpath>
        <description>
            <p>Specifies the directory where the link catalogs will be created. The link catalogs that will be read when linking the topic set are specified by <xml-element-name>/spfe/sources/link-catalogs</xml-element-name></p>
        </description>
        <build-property>spfe.directories.link-catalogs</build-property>
        <include-behavior>
            <p>The definition in the current file takes precedence over definitions in included files.</p>
        </include-behavior>
    </element-description>
    
    <element-description>
        <xpath>/spfe/build/toc-directory</xpath>
        <description>
            <p>Specifies the directory where the toc files for the topics set will be created. When building a documentation set, each topic set in the documentation set will read all the toc files in the toc directory, allowing each topic set to present a complete TOC for the entire documentation set.</p>
        </description>
        <build-property>spfe.directories.toc-directory</build-property>
        <include-behavior>
            <p>The definition in the current file takes precedence over definitions in included files.</p>
        </include-behavior>
    </element-description>
    
    <element-description>
        <xpath>/spfe/build/build-directory</xpath>
        <description>
            <p>Specifies the build directory.</p>
        </description>
        <build-property>spfe.directories.build</build-property>
        <include-behavior>
            <p>The definition in the current file takes precedence over definitions in included files.</p>
        </include-behavior>
    </element-description>
    
    <element-description>
        <xpath>/spfe/build/build-rules</xpath>
        <description>
            <p>Specifies the ANT build rules file to be used to build the current topic set.</p>
        </description>
        <build-property>spfe.build-rules</build-property>
        <include-behavior>
            <p>The definition in the current file takes precedence over definitions in included files.</p>
        </include-behavior>
    </element-description>
    
    <element-description>
        <xpath>/spfe/deployment</xpath>
        <description>
            <p>Settings related to the deployment environment (the environment into which the documentation set will be deployed.</p>
        </description>
        <build-property></build-property>
        <include-behavior>
        </include-behavior>
    </element-description>
    
    <element-description>
        <xpath>/spfe/deployment/output-path</xpath>
        <description>
            <p>The path where the topic set files will be located relative to the root of the location where the documentation set is deployed. For local build purposes, the location were the topic set files will be located is this path appended to the path specified by <xml-element-name>/spfe/build/output-directory</xml-element-name>. </p>
        </description>
        <build-property></build-property>
        <include-behavior></include-behavior>
    </element-description>
    
    <element-description>
        <xpath>/spfe/scripts</xpath>
        <description>
            <p>A container for the list of scripts to be used for each stage of the build process. Each build script for each stage should be written to use the standard SPFE interface for a script at that stage (which you can determine by examining the <file-name>spfe.rules</file-name> build rules file). Listing the full path of the script for each stage in this list will then cause that script to be called at the appropriate stage of the build process. If you need to change the interface to a script at a particular stage, you can override the build rule for that step by specifying a build rule with the same name as the one in <file-name>spfe.rules</file-name>. If you need to add additional steps, you can use the <xml-element-name>/spfe/scripts/other</xml-element-name>. If you do this, you must override the normal sequence in which the scripts are run in your local build rules file (the one specified by <xml-element-name>/spfe/build-rules</xml-element-name>.</p>
            <p>You may specify more than one script for each stage. The build will create a temporary script file that includes each of the scripts listed for each stage. One, and only one, of the included scripts must have a template named "main", which the build rule will call as the initial template (unless you have overridden the build rule for this step in your custom build file.</p>
            <p>This mechanism for building the final script by including a list of specified scripts allows you to customize the build for each topic set while maintianing a high degree of modularity and reuse in your script collections. A tyical way to use this mechanism would be to include a separate script at the presentation stage for each of the topic types included in the build. This mechanism does not prevent you from including one script file in another in the normal way, it just gives you a more flexible way of managing modular script files and assembling the right set for each topic set.</p>
        </description>
        <build-property></build-property>
        <include-behavior>
            <p>TBD</p>
        </include-behavior>
    </element-description>
    
    <element-description>
        <xpath>/spfe/scripts/synthesis</xpath>
        <description>
            <p>Container element for a list of synthesis scripts. The synthesis scripts are responsbile for assembling a set of topics in which all names are fully resolved and all conditions and inclusions have been applied.</p>
        </description>
        <build-property></build-property>
        <include-behavior></include-behavior>
    </element-description>
    
    <element-description>
        <xpath>/spfe/scripts/synthesis/script</xpath>
        <description>
            <p>
                <string id="script-description">The full path to <string-ref id-ref="script-type"/> script file.</string>
            <string-ref id-ref="script-description">
                <string id="script-type">a synthesis</string>
            </string-ref></p>
        </description>
        <build-property></build-property>
        <include-behavior></include-behavior>
    </element-description>
    
    <element-description>
        <xpath>/spfe/scripts/link-catalog</xpath>
        <description>
            <p>Container element for a list of link-catalog scripts. The link-catalog step is considered to be a sub step of the presentation process. In most cases, however, the link catalog build will be run separately from the full doc build. This is to allow you to build all the link catalogs for all the topic sets in the documenation set, so that topics can link to topics in other topic sets by reading the entire collection of link catalogs to resolve mentions.</p>
        </description>
        <build-property></build-property>
        <include-behavior></include-behavior>
    </element-description>
    
    <element-description>
        <xpath>/spfe/scripts/link-catalog/script</xpath>
        <description>
            <p><string-ref id-ref="script-description">
                <string id="script-type">a link-catalog</string>
            </string-ref></p>
        </description>
        <build-property></build-property>
        <include-behavior></include-behavior>
    </element-description>
    
    <element-description>
        <xpath>/spfe/scripts/image-list</xpath>
        <description>
            <p>A container for a list of image-list scripts. Unless you have introduced custom image handling into your system, the default image handling script should work for all topic types. The image-list script is part of the format step. It generate a list of all the graphics included in the presentation so that the build scripts can copy those graphics to the appropriate location in the output.</p>
        </description>
        <build-property></build-property>
        <include-behavior></include-behavior>
    </element-description>
    
    <element-description>
        <xpath>/spfe/scripts/image-list/script</xpath>
        <description>
            <p><string-ref id-ref="script-description">
                <string id="script-type">an image list</string>
            </string-ref></p>
        </description>
        <build-property></build-property>
        <include-behavior></include-behavior>
    </element-description>
    
    <element-description>
        <xpath>/spfe/scripts/presentation-web</xpath>
        <description>
            <p>A container for a list of presentation scripts for building a web presentation of the topic set. Usually there will be one script for the topic set as a whole and one script for each topic type in the script.</p>
        </description>
        <build-property></build-property>
        <include-behavior></include-behavior>
    </element-description>
    
    <element-description>
        <xpath>/spfe/scripts/presentation-web/script</xpath>
        <description>
            <p><string-ref id-ref="script-description">
                <string id="script-type">a web presentation</string>
            </string-ref></p>
        </description>
        <build-property></build-property>
        <include-behavior></include-behavior>
    </element-description>
    
    <element-description>
        <xpath>/spfe/scripts/presentation-book</xpath>
        <description>
            <p>A container for a list of presentation scripts for building a book presentation of the topic set. Usually there will be one script for the topic set as a whole and one script for each topic type in the script.</p>
        </description>
        <build-property></build-property>
        <include-behavior></include-behavior>
    </element-description>
    
    <element-description>
        <xpath>/spfe/scripts/presentation-book/script</xpath>
        <description>
            <p><string-ref id-ref="script-description">
                <string id="script-type">a book presentation</string>
            </string-ref></p>
        </description>
        <build-property></build-property>
        <include-behavior></include-behavior>
    </element-description>
    
    <element-description>
        <xpath>/spfe/scripts/format-html</xpath>
        <description>
            <p>A container for a list of scripts for formatting a topic set in HTML.</p>
        </description>
        <build-property></build-property>
        <include-behavior></include-behavior>
    </element-description>
    
    <element-description>
        <xpath>/spfe/scripts/format-html/script</xpath>
        <description>
            <p><string-ref id-ref="script-description">
                <string id="script-type">an html format</string>
            </string-ref>.</p>
        </description>
        <build-property></build-property>
        <include-behavior></include-behavior>
    </element-description>
    
    <element-description>
        <xpath>/spfe/scripts/format-book</xpath>
        <description>
            <p>A container for a list of formatting scripts for creating a book format of the topic set. Normally this script would produce an output in the input language of a rendering engine, such as XSL-FO or TeX. However, if you have written your own encoding script, then the formatting script should produce the input format expected by your encoding script.</p>
        </description>
        <build-property></build-property>
        <include-behavior></include-behavior>
    </element-description>
    
    <element-description>
        <xpath>/spfe/scripts/format-book/script</xpath>
        <description>
            <p><string-ref id-ref="script-description">
                <string id="script-type">a book formatting</string>
            </string-ref>.</p>
        </description>
        <build-property></build-property>
        <include-behavior></include-behavior>
    </element-description>
    
    <element-description>
        <xpath>/spfe/scripts/other</xpath>
        <description>
            <p>A container for a named list of scripts to perform an additional step that is not part of the normal SPFE build sequence. The most usual place to user other scripts is in the synthesis step for things like extracting content from source files (the way this reference is build by extracting information from the configuration schema and combining it with authored information).</p>
        </description>
        <build-property></build-property>
        <include-behavior></include-behavior>
        <attributes>
            <attribute>
                <name>name</name>
                <description>
                    <p>The name of the extra step.</p>
                </description>
            </attribute>
        </attributes>
    </element-description>
    
    <element-description>
        <xpath>/spfe/scripts/other/script</xpath>
        <description>
            <p>The full path of a script that is part of the extra step.</p>
        </description>
        <build-property></build-property>
        <include-behavior></include-behavior>
    </element-description>
    
    <element-description>
        <xpath>/spfe/format</xpath>
        <description>
            <p>A container for formatting information to be passed to the formatting scripts.</p>
        </description>
        <build-property></build-property>
        <include-behavior></include-behavior>
    </element-description>
    
    <element-description>
        <xpath>/spfe/other</xpath>
        <description>
            <p>You can use the <xml-element-name>/spfe/other</xml-element-name> element to add additional configuration settings to be used by your scripts of build files.</p>
        </description>
        <build-property>spfe.other.{name}</build-property>
        <include-behavior>
            <p>The other elements from all included files and the current file are included in the configuration.</p>
        </include-behavior>
        <attributes>
            <attribute>
                <name>name</name>
                <description>
                    <p>The name of the other configuration setting.</p>
                </description>
            </attribute>
        </attributes>
    </element-description>

    <element-description>
        <xpath>/spfe/doc-set</xpath>
        <description>
            <p>A container element for information on a documentation set. A documentation set is a collection of topic sets. To define a documentation set, you list the configuration files for each topic set in the documentation set using a <xml-element-name>/spfe/doc-set/topic-set</xml-element-name> element.</p>
            <p>To build a full documentation set, you simply run the <tool-name>spfe</tool-name> build tool with a configuration file that contains a <xml-element-name xpath="/spfe/doc-set">doc-set</xml-element-name> element directly (not via inclusion). The build tool will then run whichever build command you have specified on all the topic sets in the documentation set, as well as creating the files that belong to the documentation set as a whole.</p>
        </description>
        <build-property></build-property>
        <include-behavior>
            <p><xml-element-name>/spfe/doc-set</xml-element-name> elements in included configuration files are ignored.</p>
        </include-behavior>
    </element-description>
    
    <element-description>
        <xpath>/spfe/doc-set/title</xpath>
        <description>
            <p>The title of the documentation set.</p>
        </description>
        <build-property></build-property>
        <include-behavior></include-behavior>
    </element-description>
    
    <element-description>
        <xpath>/spfe/doc-set/topic-set</xpath>
        <description>
            <p>The path to a topic-set configuration file for a topic set to be included in the documentation set.</p>
        </description>
        <build-property></build-property>
        <include-behavior><p><xml-element-name>/spfe/doc-set</xml-element-name> elements in included configuration files are ignored.</p></include-behavior>
    </element-description>
    
    <element-description>
        <xpath>/spfe/style</xpath>
        <description>
            <p>A container element for settings related to style information used by the build tools.</p>
        </description>
        <build-property></build-property>
        <include-behavior></include-behavior>
    </element-description>
    
    
</element-descriptions>


    
