<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- This file is part of the SPFE Open Toolkit. See the accompanying license.txt file for applicable licenses.-->
<!-- (c) Copyright Analecta Communications Inc. 2012 All Rights Reserved. -->
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/css" href="../../../../spfe-docs/style/authoring/element-descriptions.css"?>
<element-descriptions
    xmlns="http://spfeopentoolkit.org/spfe-docs/schemas/config-element-descriptions"
    xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
    xsi:schemaLocation="http://spfeopentoolkit.org/spfe-docs/schemas/config-element-descriptions  http://spfeopentoolkit.org/spfe-docs/schemas/authoring/element-descriptions.xsd">
    <head>
        <uri>http://spfeopentoolkit.org/spfe-docs/schemas/config-element-descriptions/element-descriptions</uri>
        <author>Mark Baker</author>
        <status>In progress</status>
        <history>
            <revision>
                <date>2012-04-04</date>
                <author>Mark Baker</author>
                <comment>new</comment>
                <new-status>In progress</new-status>
            </revision>
            <revision>
                <date>2013-07-12</date>
                <author>jkeffer</author>
                <comment>Spelling and minor wording changes</comment>
                <new-status>In progress</new-status>
            </revision>
            <revision>
                <date>2013-07-24</date>
                <author>jkeffer</author>
                <comment>Match info in other topics and add subject affinities</comment>
                <new-status>In progress</new-status>
            </revision>
        </history>
    </head>
    <body>
        <schema-namespace>http://spfeopentoolkit.org/spfe-ot/1.0/schemas/spfe-config</schema-namespace>
        <element-description>
            <xpath>/spfe</xpath>
            <description>
                <p>The <config-setting>spfe</config-setting> element is the root element of a SPFE configuration file.</p>
                <p>You can spread your configuration over multiple configuration files. Each file must have a <config-setting>spfe</config-setting> root element. The <tool-name>spfe</tool-name> command requires a spfe configuration file as a parameter. This is the configuration file that defines the properties for an individual build. It may include more general property files that are shared by multiple builds. You include other spfe configuration files using the <config-setting>/spfe/include</config-setting> element.</p>
            </description>
            <build-property/>
            <include-behavior>
                <p/>
            </include-behavior>
        </element-description>
        <element-description>
            <xpath>/spfe/include</xpath>
            <description>
                <p>The <config-setting>include</config-setting> element is used to include other SPFE configuration files in the current configuration file. Depending on the include behavior for each element, the elements in the current file will either be added to the elements in the included file or will replace the elements in the included file. See the <bold>Include Behavior</bold> section of each entry in this reference to see how each element is handled.</p>
            </description>
            <build-property/>
            <include-behavior>
                <p>When an included file is read, any includes in that file are read as well. Be careful not to create circular includes.</p>
            </include-behavior>
            <attributes>
                <attribute>
                    <name>href</name>
                    <description>
                        <p>The URL of the file to load. Note that XML Catalogs are not used to
                            resolve this URL. To ensure portability of your configuration file,
                            either use a relative URL or use
                            <config-setting>/spfe/define</config-setting> to
                            create a constant for the root of the file path.</p>
                    </description>
                </attribute>
            </attributes>
        </element-description>
        <element-description>
            <xpath>/spfe/define</xpath>
            <description>
                <p>The <config-setting>define</config-setting> element is used
                    to define string constants that can be used to define other properties. </p>
                <p> For example,
                    <code><![CDATA[<define name="SPFE_BUILD" value="${HOME}/spfebuild/build"/>]]></code>/></p>
                <p>To use a defined value in setting another property you surround the property name
                    with <code>${</code> and <code>}</code>, as in the use of the <code>HOME</code>
                    constant in the example above. The variables <code>HOME</code> (the user's home
                    directory) and <code>SPFEOT_HOME</code> (the location of the SPFE Open Toolkit)
                    are predefined. (<code>HOME</code> is taken from the operating system, and you
                    must set an environment variable <code>SPFTOT_HOME</code> when you <task>install
                        the SPFE Open Toolkit</task>).</p>
                <p>You can use one constant to define the value of another constant. The build tools
                    will raise an error if a circular definition is found. (That is, don't define A
                    using B and then try to define B using A.)</p>
            </description>
            <build-property/>
            <include-behavior>
                <p>Definitions from included files are added to the definitions in the current file and the combined set of definitions is used to expand constants in the property definitions in all files; it makes no difference where a particular constant is defined.</p> <p>A definition in the current file with the same name as a definition in an included file overrides the definition from an included file.</p>
            </include-behavior>
            <attributes>
                <attribute>
                    <name>name</name>
                    <description>
                        <p>The name of the constant you are defining. The name must conform to the XML NCName type. In practice, for visibility, it should consist of upper case letters and underscores, with no spaces.</p>
                    </description>
                </attribute>
                <attribute>
                    <name>value</name>
                    <description>
                        <p>The value of the constant. This can be anything you like, and you may include other constants in the value of the constant you are defining, as long as you do not create a circular definition. The value will be substituted for the constant wherever it occurs as a straight string substitution.</p>
                    </description>
                </attribute>
            </attributes>
        </element-description>
        <element-description>
            <xpath>/spfe/topic-set-id</xpath>
            <description>
                <p>The <config-setting>topic-set-id</config-setting> element
                    specifies the identifier for the current <feature>topic set</feature>. This
                    identifier can be used to create a reference to the topic set. It is also used
                    to create file and directory names, so it should be a value that is a valid file
                    name (minus the extension) on all target operating systems.</p>
            </description>
            <build-property>spfe.topic-set-id</build-property>
            <include-behavior>
                <p>The value in the current file takes precedence over the value in the included file.</p>
            </include-behavior>
        </element-description>
        <element-description>
            <xpath>/spfe/topic-type-order</xpath>
            <description>
                <p>The order in which topic types are listed in the table of contents if <feature>topic type ordering</feature> is used. For this element to take effect, you need to define <config-setting>/spfe/sources/tocs</config-setting>.</p>
            </description>
            <build-property/>
            <include-behavior>
                <p>The value in the current configuration file overrides values in any included configuration files.</p>
            </include-behavior>
        </element-description>
        <element-description>
            <xpath>/spfe/sources</xpath>
            <description>
                <p>A container element for settings that point to various source files used in the build.</p>
            </description>
            <build-property/>
            <include-behavior>
                <p>The sub-elements in the current file individually take precedence over the same sub-element in an included file. This means that you cannot override the entire <config-setting>sources</config-setting> element in the current file, only the individual sub files.</p>
            </include-behavior>
        </element-description>

        <element-description>
            <xpath>/spfe/sources/topics</xpath>
            <description>
                <p>A container element for a list of file selectors that select the topic files to include in the build. Becomes an ANT <ant-element>fileset</ant-element> expression in the build file.</p>
            </description>
            <build-property>topics</build-property>
            <include-behavior>
                <p>The set of file selectors from included configuration files are added to the file selectors in the current configuration file.</p>
            </include-behavior>
        </element-description>

        <element-description>
            <xpath>/spfe/sources/topics/include</xpath>
            <description>
                <p>A path expression indicating topic files to include in the build. You can use wild cards. This path expression is used to create an <config-setting>include</config-setting> element in an ANT <ant-element>files</ant-element> element that is used to copy topic files to the build directory for inclusion in the build.</p>
            </description>
            <build-property/>
            <include-behavior>
                <p>The set of file selectors from included configuration files are added to the file selectors in the current configuration file.</p>
            </include-behavior>
        </element-description>


        <element-description>
            <xpath>/spfe/sources/text-objects</xpath>
            <description>
                <p>A container element for a list of file selectors that select the text-object
                    files to include in the build. Becomes an ANT
                    <ant-element>fileset</ant-element> expression in
                    the build file.</p>
            </description>
            <build-property>text-objects</build-property>
            <include-behavior>
                <p>The set of file selectors from included configuration files are added to the file selectors in the current configuration file.</p>
            </include-behavior>
        </element-description>

        <element-description>
            <xpath>/spfe/sources/text-objects/include</xpath>
            <description>
                <p>A path expression indicating <feature>text object</feature> files to include in the build. You can use wild cards. This path expression is used to create an <config-setting>include</config-setting> element in an ANT <ant-element>files</ant-element> element that is used to copy text object files to the build directory for inclusion in the build.</p>
            </description>
            <build-property/>
            <include-behavior>
                <p>The set of file selectors from included configuration files are added to the file selectors in the current configuration file.</p>
            </include-behavior>
        </element-description>

        <element-description>
            <xpath>/spfe/sources/fragments</xpath>
            <description>
                <p>A container element for a list of file selectors that select the fragment files
                    to include in the build. Becomes an ANT
                    <ant-element>fileset</ant-element> expression in
                    the build file.</p>
            </description>
            <build-property>fragments</build-property>
            <include-behavior>
                <p>The set of file selectors from included configuration files are added to the file selectors in the current configuration file.</p>
            </include-behavior>
        </element-description>

        <element-description>
            <xpath>/spfe/sources/fragments/include</xpath>
            <description>
                <p>A path expression indicating fragment files to include in the build. You can use wild cards. This path expression is used to create an <config-setting>include</config-setting> element in an ANT <ant-element>files</ant-element> element that is used to copy fragment files to the build directory for inclusion in the build.</p>
            </description>
            <build-property/>
            <include-behavior>
                <p>The set of file selectors from included configuration files are added to the file selectors in the current configuration file.</p>
            </include-behavior>
        </element-description>

        <element-description>
            <xpath>/spfe/sources/images</xpath>
            <description>
                <p>Specifies the location of images that can be used in the build. Note that only the images actually referenced in the text (either via hard linking or soft linking) will be included in the build itself. This setting just tells the build where to look for images.</p>
            </description>
            <build-property>spfe.directories.image-source</build-property>
            <include-behavior>
                <p>The definition in the current file takes precedence over definitions in included files.</p>
            </include-behavior>
        </element-description>

        <element-description>
            <xpath>/spfe/sources/graphics</xpath>
            <description>
                <p>A container element for a list of file selectors that select the graphics files to be included in the build. Becomes an ANT <ant-element>fileset</ant-element> expression in the build file.</p>
            </description>
            <build-property>graphics</build-property>
            <include-behavior>
                <p>The set of file selectors from included configuration files are added to the file selectors in the current configuration file.</p>
            </include-behavior>
        </element-description>

        <element-description>
            <xpath>/spfe/sources/graphics/include</xpath>
            <description>
                <p>A path expression indicating graphics files to include in the build. You can use wild cards. This path expression is used to create an <config-setting>include</config-setting> element in an ANT <ant-element>files</ant-element> element that is used to copy graphics files to the build directory for inclusion in the build.</p>
            </description>
            <build-property/>
            <include-behavior>
                <p>The set of file selectors from included configuration files are added to the file selectors in the current configuration file.</p>
            </include-behavior>
        </element-description>

        <element-description>
            <xpath>/spfe/sources/graphics-catalog</xpath>
            <description>
                <p>A container element for a list of file selectors that select the graphics-catalog files to be included in the build. Becomes an ANT <ant-element>fileset</ant-element> expression in the build file.</p>
            </description>
            <build-property>graphics-catalog</build-property>
            <include-behavior>
                <p>The set of file selectors from included configuration files are added to the file selectors in the current configuration file.</p>
            </include-behavior>
        </element-description>

        <element-description>
            <xpath>/spfe/sources/graphics-catalog/include</xpath>
            <description>
                <p>A path expression indicating <feature>graphics catalog</feature> files to include in the build. You can use wild cards. This path expression is used to create an <config-setting>include</config-setting> element in an ANT <ant-element>files</ant-element> element that is used to copy <feature>graphics catalog</feature> files to the build directory for inclusion in the build.</p>
            </description>
            <build-property/>
            <include-behavior>
                <p>The set of file selectors from included configuration files are added to the file selectors in the current configuration file.</p>
            </include-behavior>
        </element-description>

        <element-description>
            <xpath>/spfe/sources/strings</xpath>
            <description>
                <p>A container element for a list of file selectors that select the strings files to be included in the build. Becomes an ANT <ant-element>fileset</ant-element> expression in the build file.</p>
            </description>
            <build-property>strings</build-property>
            <include-behavior>
                <p>The set of file selectors from included configuration files are added to the file selectors in the current configuration file.</p>
            </include-behavior>
        </element-description>

        <element-description>
            <xpath>/spfe/sources/strings/include</xpath>
            <description>
                <p>A path expression indicating <feature>strings</feature> files to include in the build. You can use wild cards. This path expression is used to create an <config-setting>include</config-setting> element in an ANT <ant-element>files</ant-element> element that is used to copy <feature>strings</feature> files to the build directory for inclusion in the build.</p>
            </description>
            <build-property/>
            <include-behavior>
                <p>The set of file selectors from included configuration files are added to the file selectors in the current configuration file.</p>
            </include-behavior>
        </element-description>

        <element-description>
            <xpath>/spfe/sources/link-catalogs</xpath>
            <description>
                <p>A container element for a list of file selectors that select the link-catalog
                    files to be used for linking topics. The setting becomes an ANT
                    <ant-element>files</ant-element> expression in the
                    build file.</p>
                <p>The link catalogs for the current topic set will be created in the location
                    specified by
                    <config-setting>/spfe/build/link-catalog-directory</config-setting>.
                    Make sure that the path specified by
                    <config-setting>spfe/build/link-catalog-directory</config-setting>
                    is included in those specified by
                    <config-setting>/spfe/sources/link-catalogs</config-setting>.</p>
                <p>You can also include link catalogs for other topic sets in the documentation set,
                    or link catalogs from other documentation sets, in the list of link catalogs
                    used to link the current topic set. The simplest way to have the entire
                    documentation set use the same link catalogs is to set
                    <config-setting>/spfe/sources/link-catalogs</config-setting>
                    and
                    <config-setting>spfe/build/link-catalog-directory</config-setting>
                    to the same directory, and to define them both in the main configuration file
                    for the documentation set. If you do not define a link catalog element, the
                    build does not generate links.</p>
            </description>
            <build-property>link-catalogs</build-property>
            <include-behavior>
                <p>The set of file selectors from included configuration files are added to the file selectors in the current configuration file.</p>
            </include-behavior>
        </element-description>

        <element-description>
            <xpath>/spfe/sources/link-catalogs/include</xpath>
            <description>
                <p>A path expression indicating <feature>link catalog</feature> files to include in
                    the build. You can use wild cards. This path expression is used to create an
                    <config-setting>include</config-setting> element in an ANT
                    <ant-element>files</ant-element> element that is
                    used to copy <feature>link catalog</feature> files to the build directory for
                    inclusion in the build.</p>
            </description>
            <build-property/>
            <include-behavior>
                <p>The set of file selectors from included configuration files are added to the file selectors in the current configuration file.</p>
            </include-behavior>
        </element-description>

        <element-description>
            <xpath>/spfe/sources/tocs</xpath>
            <description>
                <p>A container element for a list of file selectors that select the <feature>TOC
                        files</feature> to be used for creating tables of contents. The setting
                    becomes an ANT <ant-element>files</ant-element>
                    expression in the build file.</p>
                <p>The TOC file for the current topic set will be created in the location specified
                    by
                    <config-setting>/spfe/build/toc-directory</config-setting>.
                    Make sure that the path specified by
                    <config-setting>spfe/build/toc-directory</config-setting> is
                    included in those specified by
                    <config-setting>/spfe/sources/tocs</config-setting>.</p>
                <p>You can also include TOC files for other topic sets in the documentation set, or
                    TOCs from other documentation sets, in the list of TOCs used in the current
                    topic set. The simplest way to have the entire documentation set use the same
                    TOC files is to set
                    <config-setting>/spfe/sources/tocs</config-setting> and
                    <config-setting>spfe/build/toc-directory</config-setting> to
                    the same directory, and to define them both in the shared configuration file for
                    the documentation set. If you do not define a tocs element, the output does not
                    show a table of contents; the build generates the toc files, but the
                    presentation scripts do not include them.</p>
            </description>
            <build-property>tocs</build-property>
            <include-behavior>
                <p>The set of file selectors from included configuration files are added to the file selectors in the current configuration file.</p>
            </include-behavior>
        </element-description>

        <element-description>
            <xpath>/spfe/sources/tocs/include</xpath>
            <description>
                <p>A path expression indicating <feature>TOC files</feature> to include in the build. You can use wild cards. This path expression is used to create an <config-setting>include</config-setting> element in an ANT <ant-element>files</ant-element> element that is used to copy <feature>TOC files</feature> to the build directory for inclusion in the build.</p>
            </description>
            <build-property/>
            <include-behavior>
                <p>The set of file selectors from included configuration files are added to the file selectors in the current configuration file.</p>
            </include-behavior>
        </element-description>

        <element-description>
            <xpath>/spfe/sources/synonyms</xpath>
            <description>
                <p>A container element for a list of file selectors that select the synonyms files to be included in the build. Becomes an ANT <ant-element>fileset</ant-element> expression in the build file.</p>
            </description>
            <build-property>synonyms</build-property>
            <include-behavior>
                <p>The set of file selectors from included configuration files are added to the file selectors in the current configuration file.</p>
            </include-behavior>
        </element-description>

        <element-description>
            <xpath>/spfe/sources/synonyms/include</xpath>
            <description>
                <p>A path expression indicating <feature>synonyms</feature> files to include in the build. You can use wild cards. This path expression is used to create an <config-setting>include</config-setting> element in an ANT <ant-element>files</ant-element> element that is used to copy <feature>synonyms</feature> files to the build directory for inclusion in the build.</p>
            </description>
            <build-property/>
            <include-behavior>
                <p>The set of file selectors from included configuration files are added to the file selectors in the current configuration file.</p>
            </include-behavior>
        </element-description>

        <element-description>
            <xpath>/spfe/sources/other</xpath>
            <description>
                <p>A container element for a list of file selectors that select other files to be included in the build. The name of the set of files is specified by the <config-setting>name</config-setting> attribute. Becomes an ANT <ant-element>fileset</ant-element> expression in the build file.</p>
            </description>
            <build-property>other.{name}</build-property>
            <include-behavior>
                <p>The set of file selectors from included configuration files are added to the file selectors in the current configuration file.</p>
            </include-behavior>
            <attributes>
                <attribute>
                    <name>name</name>
                    <description>
                        <p>The name of the type of other source.</p>
                    </description>
                </attribute>
            </attributes>
        </element-description>

        <element-description>
            <xpath>/spfe/sources/other/include</xpath>
            <description>
                <p>A path expression indicating other files to include in the build. You can use wild cards. This path expression is used to create an <config-setting>include</config-setting> element in an ANT <ant-element>files</ant-element> element that is used to copy other files to the build directory for inclusion in the build.</p>
            </description>
            <build-property/>
            <include-behavior>
                <p>The set of file selectors from included configuration files are added to the file selectors in the current configuration file.</p>
            </include-behavior>
        </element-description>

        <element-description>
            <xpath>/spfe/condition-tokens</xpath>
            <description>
                <p>The <config-setting>condition-tokens</config-setting> element specifies the <feature>condition tokens</feature> that will be applied to the build.</p>
            </description>
            <build-property/>
            <include-behavior>
                <p>The value from the current config file overrides the values in included files.</p>
            </include-behavior>
        </element-description>

        <element-description>
            <xpath>/spfe/default-topic-scope</xpath>
            <description>
                <p>Specifies the <feature>topic scope</feature> tokens to be applied to all topics in the build by default. Effectively, specifying this setting applies scope to topics that do not specify a scope. Topics that declare their own scope are not affected by this setting.</p>
            </description>
            <build-property/>
            <include-behavior>
                <p>The value from the current config file overrides the values in included files.</p>
            </include-behavior>
        </element-description>

        <element-description>
            <xpath>/spfe/default-subject-affinity-scope</xpath>
            <description>
                <p>Specifies the <feature>subject-affinity scope</feature> tokens to be applied to all subject-affinities in all topics in the build by default. Effectively, specifying this setting applies scope to subject-affinities that do not specify a scope. Subject affinities that declare their own scope are not affected by this setting.</p>
            </description>
            <build-property/>
            <include-behavior>
                <p>The value from the current config file overrides the values in included files.</p>
            </include-behavior>
        </element-description>

        <element-description>
            <xpath>/spfe/output-formats</xpath>
            <description>
                <p>Specifies the output formats to be created. Valid values are <code>html</code>,
                    <code>pdf</code>, <code>chm</code>, and <code>epub</code>.</p>
            </description>
            <build-property/>
            <include-behavior>
                <p>The value from the current config file overrides the values in included files.</p>
            </include-behavior>
        </element-description>

        <element-description>
            <xpath>/spfe/topic-type-aliases</xpath>
            <description>
                <p>Topic types in SPFE are identified by the namespace identifier of the topic
                    schema. In some cases, however, we need to display the topic type to the user.
                    For this purpose we need a user-friendly alias for the topic type. The
                    <config-setting>topic-type-aliases</config-setting> element
                    is a container for a list of topic type aliases that the build scripts can use
                    to display a user-friendly name for a topic type.</p>
            </description>
            <build-property/>
            <include-behavior>
                <p>The build scripts combine the items in the topic type alias list from the current
                    and all included configuration files into a single list. In the event that there
                    is more than one instance of same topic type, the first definition in the
                    configuration file highest in the include sequence will be used.</p>
            </include-behavior>
        </element-description>

        <element-description>
            <xpath>/spfe/topic-type-aliases/topic-type</xpath>
            <description>
                <p>A container for the settings for each item in the <feature>topic type
                        alias</feature> list.</p>
            </description>
            <build-property/>
            <include-behavior/>
        </element-description>

        <element-description>
            <xpath>/spfe/topic-type-aliases/topic-type/id</xpath>
            <description>
                <p>The topic type id, that is, the namespace identifier of the topic type schema.</p>
            </description>
            <build-property/>
            <include-behavior/>
        </element-description>

        <element-description>
            <xpath>/spfe/topic-type-aliases/topic-type/alias</xpath>
            <description>
                <p>The alias for the topic type <config-setting xpath="/spfe/topic-type-aliases/topic-type/id">id</config-setting>, that is, a reader-friendly name for the topic type.</p>
            </description>
            <build-property/>
            <include-behavior/>
        </element-description>

        <element-description>
            <xpath>/spfe/topic-type-aliases/topic-type/plural</xpath>
            <description>
                <p>The plural version of the <config-setting xpath="/spfe/topic-type-aliases/topic-type/alias">alias</config-setting> for the topic type <config-setting xpath="/spfe/topic-type-aliases/topic-type/id">id</config-setting>.</p>
            </description>
            <build-property/>
            <include-behavior/>
        </element-description>

        <element-description>
            <xpath>/spfe/messages</xpath>
            <description>
                <p>Specifies the types of messages that will be generated by the build. Possible value are <code>info</code>, and <code>warning</code>.</p>
            </description>
            <build-property>spfe.message-types</build-property>
            <include-behavior>
                <p>The definition in the current file takes precedence over definitions in included files.</p>
            </include-behavior>
        </element-description>

        <element-description>
            <xpath>/spfe/wip-site</xpath>
            <description>
                <p>A container element for configuration information on the <feature>work in progress site</feature>.</p>
            </description>
            <build-property/>
            <include-behavior>
                <p>TBD</p>
            </include-behavior>
        </element-description>

        <element-description>
            <xpath>/spfe/wip-site/href</xpath>
            <description>
                <p>The href of the <feature>work in progress site</feature>.</p>
            </description>
            <build-property>spfe.wip-site.href</build-property>
            <include-behavior/>
        </element-description>

        <element-description>
            <xpath>/spfe/wip-site/ftp</xpath>
            <description>
                <p>A container for login information for FTP access to the <feature>work in progress site</feature>.</p>
            </description>
            <build-property/>
            <include-behavior/>
        </element-description>

        <element-description>
            <xpath>/spfe/wip-site/ftp/url</xpath>
            <description>
                <p>The URL of the ftp login to the <feature>work in progress site</feature>.</p>
            </description>
            <build-property>spfe.wip-site.ftp.url</build-property>
            <include-behavior/>
        </element-description>

        <element-description>
            <xpath>/spfe/wip-site/ftp/user</xpath>
            <description>
                <p>The user name for logging in to the <feature>work in progress site</feature>.</p>
            </description>
            <build-property>spfe.wip-site.ftp.user</build-property>
            <include-behavior/>
        </element-description>

        <element-description>
            <xpath>/spfe/wip-site/ftp/password</xpath>
            <description>
                <p>The ftp password for the <feature>work in progress site</feature>.</p>
            </description>
            <build-property>spfe.wip-site.ftp.password</build-property>
            <include-behavior/>
        </element-description>


        <element-description>
            <xpath>/spfe/wip-site/path</xpath>
            <description>
                <p>The file path to the root of the <feature>work in progress site</feature>.</p>
            </description>
            <build-property>spfe.wip-site.path</build-property>
            <include-behavior/>
        </element-description>

        <element-description>
            <xpath>/spfe/build</xpath>
            <description>
                <p>A container element for settings related to the build environment.</p>
            </description>
            <build-property/>
            <include-behavior/>
        </element-description>

        <element-description>
            <xpath>/spfe/build/output-directory</xpath>
            <description>
                <p>Specifies the directory where the final build output will be created.</p>
            </description>
            <build-property>spfe.directories.output</build-property>
            <include-behavior>
                <p>The definition in the current file takes precedence over definitions in included files.</p>
            </include-behavior>
        </element-description>

        <element-description>
            <xpath>/spfe/build/link-catalog-directory</xpath>
            <description>
                <p>Specifies the directory where the link catalogs will be created. The link catalogs that will be read when linking the topic set are specified by <config-setting>/spfe/sources/link-catalogs</config-setting>.</p>
            </description>
            <build-property>spfe.directories.link-catalogs</build-property>
            <include-behavior>
                <p>The definition in the current file takes precedence over definitions in included files.</p>
            </include-behavior>
        </element-description>

        <element-description>
            <xpath>/spfe/build/toc-directory</xpath>
            <description>
                <p>Specifies the directory where the TOC files will be created by the topic set build. The TOCs that will be read when linking the topic set are specified by <config-setting>/spfe/sources/tocs</config-setting>.</p>
            </description>
            <build-property>spfe.directories.toc-directory</build-property>
            <include-behavior>
                <p>The definition in the current file takes precedence over definitions in included files.</p>
            </include-behavior>
        </element-description>

        <element-description>
            <xpath>/spfe/build/build-directory</xpath>
            <description>
                <p>Specifies the <feature>build directory</feature> used to store temporary files
                    (logs, fully resolved configuration files, scripts) generated during the build
                    process. The default is the value of
                    <config-setting>/spfe/topic-set-id</config-setting> appended
                    to the value of
                    <config-setting>/spfe/doc-set element</config-setting>
                    appended to the value of the environment variable
                    <code>SPFE_BUILD_DIR</code>.</p>
            </description>
            <build-property>spfe.directories.build</build-property>
            <include-behavior>
                <p>The definition in the current file takes precedence over definitions in included files.</p>
            </include-behavior>
        </element-description>

        <element-description>
            <xpath>/spfe/build/build-rules</xpath>
            <description>
                <p>Specifies the ANT build rules file to use to build the current topic set.</p>
            </description>
            <build-property>spfe.build-rules</build-property>
            <include-behavior>
                <p>The definition in the current file takes precedence over definitions in included files.</p>
            </include-behavior>
        </element-description>

        <element-description>
            <xpath>/spfe/deployment</xpath>
            <description>
                <p>Settings related to the deployment environment (the environment into which the
                    documentation set will be deployed).</p>
            </description>
            <build-property/>
            <include-behavior> </include-behavior>
        </element-description>

        <element-description>
            <xpath>/spfe/deployment/output-path</xpath>
            <description>
                <p>The path where the topic set files will be located relative to the root of the
                    location where the documentation set is deployed. For local build purposes, the
                    location of the topic set files is the value of this path appended to the path
                    specified by
                    <config-setting>/spfe/build/output-directory</config-setting>.</p>
            </description>
            <build-property/>
            <include-behavior/>
        </element-description>

        <element-description>
            <xpath>/spfe/scripts</xpath>
            <description>
                <p>A container for the list of scripts to be used for each stage of the build process. Each build script for each stage should be written to use the standard SPFE interface for a script at that stage (which you can determine by examining the <file-name>spfe.rules</file-name> build rules file). Listing the full path of the script for each stage in this list will then cause that script to be called at the appropriate stage of the build process. If you need to change the interface to a script at a particular stage, you can override the build rule for that step by specifying a build rule with the same name as the one in <file-name>spfe.rules</file-name>. If you need to add additional steps, you can use the <config-setting>/spfe/scripts/other</config-setting>. If you do this, you must override the normal sequence in which the scripts are run in your local build rules file (the one specified by <config-setting>/spfe/build/build-rules</config-setting>).</p>
                <p>You may specify more than one script for each stage. The build will create a temporary script file that includes each of the scripts listed for each stage. One, and only one, of the included scripts must have a template named "main", which the build rule will call as the initial template (unless you have overridden the build rule for this step in your custom build file.</p>
                <p>This mechanism for building the final script by including a list of specified scripts allows you to customize the build for each topic set while maintaining a high degree of modularity and reuse in your script collections. A typical way to use this mechanism would be to include a separate script at the presentation stage for each of the topic types included in the build. This mechanism does not prevent you from including one script file in another in the normal way, it just gives you a more flexible way of managing modular script files and assembling the right set for each topic set.</p>
            </description>
            <build-property/>
            <include-behavior>
                <p>TBD</p>
            </include-behavior>
        </element-description>

        <element-description>
            <xpath>/spfe/scripts/synthesis</xpath>
            <description>
                <p>Container element for a list of synthesis scripts. The synthesis scripts are responsible for assembling a set of topics in which all names are fully resolved and all conditions and inclusions have been applied.</p>
            </description>
            <build-property/>
            <include-behavior/>
        </element-description>

        <element-description>
            <xpath>/spfe/scripts/synthesis/script</xpath>
            <description>
                <p> <string id="script-description">The full path to <string-ref id-ref="script-type"/> script file.</string> <string-ref id-ref="script-description"> <string id="script-type">a synthesis</string> </string-ref></p>
            </description>
            <build-property/>
            <include-behavior/>
        </element-description>

        <element-description>
            <xpath>/spfe/scripts/link-catalog</xpath>
            <description>
                <p>Container element for a list of link-catalog scripts. The link-catalog step is considered to be a sub step of the presentation process. In most cases, however, the link catalog build will be run separately from the full doc build. This is to allow you to build all the link catalogs for all the topic sets in the documentation set, so that topics can link to topics in other topic sets by reading the entire collection of link catalogs to resolve subject-affinities.</p>
            </description>
            <build-property/>
            <include-behavior/>
        </element-description>

        <element-description>
            <xpath>/spfe/scripts/link-catalog/script</xpath>
            <description>
                <p><string-ref id-ref="script-description"> <string id="script-type">a link-catalog</string> </string-ref></p>
            </description>
            <build-property/>
            <include-behavior/>
        </element-description>
        <element-description>
            <xpath>/spfe/scripts/toc</xpath>
            <description>
                <p>A container for a list of scripts for creating a <feature>table of contents file</feature> for the topic set. </p>
            </description>
            <build-property/>
            <include-behavior/>
        </element-description>
        <element-description>
            <xpath>/spfe/scripts/toc/script</xpath>
            <description>
                <p><string-ref id-ref="script-description"> <string id="script-type">a TOC file</string> </string-ref></p>
            </description>
            <build-property/>
            <include-behavior/>
        </element-description>

        <element-description>
            <xpath>/spfe/scripts/image-list</xpath>
            <description>
                <p>A container for a list of image-list scripts. Unless you have introduced custom
                    image handling into your system, the default image handling script should work
                    for all topic types. The image-list script is part of the format step. It
                    generates a list of all the graphics included in the presentation so that the
                    build scripts can copy those graphics to the appropriate location in the
                    output.</p>
            </description>
            <build-property/>
            <include-behavior/>
        </element-description>

        <element-description>
            <xpath>/spfe/scripts/image-list/script</xpath>
            <description>
                <p><string-ref id-ref="script-description"> <string id="script-type">an image list</string> </string-ref></p>
            </description>
            <build-property/>
            <include-behavior/>
        </element-description>

        <element-description>
            <xpath>/spfe/scripts/presentation-web</xpath>
            <description>
                <p>A container for a list of presentation scripts for building a web presentation of the topic set. Usually there will be one script for the topic set as a whole and one script for each topic type in the script.</p>
            </description>
            <build-property/>
            <include-behavior/>
        </element-description>

        <element-description>
            <xpath>/spfe/scripts/presentation-web/script</xpath>
            <description>
                <p><string-ref id-ref="script-description"> <string id="script-type">a web presentation</string> </string-ref></p>
            </description>
            <build-property/>
            <include-behavior/>
        </element-description>

        <element-description>
            <xpath>/spfe/scripts/presentation-book</xpath>
            <description>
                <p>A container for a list of presentation scripts for building a book presentation of the topic set. Usually there will be one script for the topic set as a whole and one script for each topic type in the script.</p>
            </description>
            <build-property/>
            <include-behavior/>
        </element-description>

        <element-description>
            <xpath>/spfe/scripts/presentation-book/script</xpath>
            <description>
                <p><string-ref id-ref="script-description"> <string id="script-type">a book presentation</string> </string-ref></p>
            </description>
            <build-property/>
            <include-behavior/>
        </element-description>

        <element-description>
            <xpath>/spfe/scripts/format-html</xpath>
            <description>
                <p>A container for a list of scripts for formatting a topic set in HTML.</p>
            </description>
            <build-property/>
            <include-behavior/>
        </element-description>

        <element-description>
            <xpath>/spfe/scripts/format-html/script</xpath>
            <description>
                <p><string-ref id-ref="script-description"> <string id="script-type">an html format</string> </string-ref>.</p>
            </description>
            <build-property/>
            <include-behavior/>
        </element-description>

        <element-description>
            <xpath>/spfe/scripts/format-book</xpath>
            <description>
                <p>A container for a list of formatting scripts for creating a book format of the topic set. Normally this script would produce an output in the input language of a rendering engine, such as XSL-FO or TeX. However, if you have written your own encoding script, then the formatting script should produce the input format expected by your encoding script.</p>
            </description>
            <build-property/>
            <include-behavior/>
        </element-description>

        <element-description>
            <xpath>/spfe/scripts/format-book/script</xpath>
            <description>
                <p><string-ref id-ref="script-description"> <string id="script-type">a book formatting</string> </string-ref>.</p>
            </description>
            <build-property/>
            <include-behavior/>
        </element-description>

        <element-description>
            <xpath>/spfe/scripts/other</xpath>
            <description>
                <p>A container for a named list of scripts to perform an additional step that is not part of the normal SPFE build sequence. The most usual place to user other scripts is in the synthesis step for things like extracting content from source files (the way this reference is build by extracting information from the configuration schema and combining it with authored information).</p>
            </description>
            <build-property/>
            <include-behavior/>
            <attributes>
                <attribute>
                    <name>name</name>
                    <description>
                        <p>The name of the extra step.</p>
                    </description>
                </attribute>
            </attributes>
        </element-description>

        <element-description>
            <xpath>/spfe/scripts/other/script</xpath>
            <description>
                <p>The full path of a script that is part of the extra step.</p>
            </description>
            <build-property/>
            <include-behavior/>
        </element-description>

        <element-description>
            <xpath>/spfe/format</xpath>
            <description>
                <p>A container for formatting information to be passed to the formatting scripts.</p>
            </description>
            <build-property/>
            <include-behavior/>
        </element-description>

        <element-description>
            <xpath>/spfe/other</xpath>
            <description>
                <p>You can use the <config-setting>/spfe/other</config-setting> element to add additional configuration settings to be used by your scripts of build files.</p>
            </description>
            <build-property>spfe.other.{name}</build-property>
            <include-behavior>
                <p>The other elements from all included files and the current file are included in the configuration.</p>
            </include-behavior>
            <attributes>
                <attribute>
                    <name>name</name>
                    <description>
                        <p>The name of the other configuration setting.</p>
                    </description>
                </attribute>
            </attributes>
        </element-description>

        <element-description>
            <xpath>/spfe/doc-set</xpath>
            <description>
                <p>A container element for information on a documentation set. A documentation set
                    is a collection of <feature>topic sets</feature>. To define a documentation set,
                    you list the configuration files for each topic set in the documentation set
                    using a
                    <config-setting>/spfe/doc-set/topic-sets/topic-set</config-setting>
                    element.</p>
                <p>To build a full documentation set, you simply run the <tool-name>spfe</tool-name>
                    build tool with a configuration file that contains a
                    <config-setting xpath="/spfe/doc-set">doc-set</config-setting>
                    element directly (not via inclusion). The build tool will then run whichever
                    build command you have specified on all the topic sets in the documentation set,
                    as well as creating the files that belong to the documentation set as a
                    whole.</p>
            </description>
            <build-property/>
            <include-behavior>
                <p><config-setting>/spfe/doc-set</config-setting> elements in included configuration files are ignored.</p>
            </include-behavior>
            <attributes>
                <attribute>
                    <name>id</name>
                    <description>
                        <p>An ID for the <feature>documentation set</feature>. This value is used as
                            the name of a directory containing the documentation set build inside
                            the <feature>build directory</feature>.</p>
                    </description>
                </attribute>
            </attributes>
        </element-description>

        <element-description>        
            <xpath>/spfe/doc-set/title</xpath>
            <description>
                <p>The title of the <feature>documentation set</feature>.</p>
            </description>
            <build-property/>
            <include-behavior/>
        </element-description>
        <element-description>
            <xpath>/spfe/doc-set/topic-sets</xpath>
            <description>
                <p>A container element for the list of <feature>topic sets</feature> in a <feature>documentation set</feature>.</p>
            </description>
            <build-property/>
            <include-behavior/>
        </element-description>
        <element-description>
            <xpath>/spfe/doc-set/topic-sets/topic-set/id</xpath>
            <description>
                <p>The topic set id of the included <feature>topic set</feature>, it should normally match the <config-setting>/spfe/topic-set-id</config-setting> element in the topic set's configuration file. It is also used to form file names and should be a valid file name on all target operating systems.</p>
            </description>
            <build-property/>
            <include-behavior/>
        </element-description>
        <element-description>
            <xpath>/spfe/doc-set/topic-sets/topic-set/href</xpath>
            <description>
                <p>The URL of the configuration file for the included <feature>topic set</feature>.</p>
            </description>
            <build-property/>
            <include-behavior/>
        </element-description>

        <element-description>
            <xpath>/spfe/doc-set/topic-sets/topic-set</xpath>
            <description>
                <p>The path to a topic set configuration file for a <feature>topic set</feature> to
                    be included in the <feature>documentation set</feature>.</p>
            </description>
            <build-property/>
            <include-behavior>
                <p><config-setting>/spfe/doc-set</config-setting> elements in included configuration files are ignored.</p>
            </include-behavior>
        </element-description>

        <element-description>
            <xpath>/spfe/style</xpath>
            <description>
                <p>A container element for settings related to style information used by the build tools.</p>
            </description>
            <build-property/>
            <include-behavior/>
        </element-description>

        <element-description>
            <xpath>/spfe/style/html-style-directories</xpath>
            <description>
                <p>A container element for a list of directories containing style files for HTML output. The specified directories will be copied into a <directory-name>style</directory-name> directory in the output directory. All subdirectories and their files will be copied as well. In the build file, it becomes an ANT <ant-element>resources</ant-element> element with the <ant-element>id</ant-element> of <code>spfe.style.html-style-directories</code>.</p>
            </description>
            <build-property>spfe.style.html-style-directories</build-property>
            <include-behavior>
                <p>Entries in included files will be added to the those in the including file.</p>
            </include-behavior>
        </element-description>

        <element-description>
            <xpath>/spfe/style/html-style-directories/include</xpath>
            <description>
                <p>A path expression indicating style directories to be copied to the output. This path expression is used to create an <config-setting>include</config-setting> element in an ANT <ant-element>resources</ant-element> element that is used to copy style files to the output directory.</p>
            </description>
            <build-property/>
            <include-behavior>
                <p>Entries in included files will be added to the those in the including file.</p>
            </include-behavior>
        </element-description>
        <element-description>
            <xpath>/spfe/topic-set-type</xpath>
            <description>
                <p>This setting enables you to assign a type string to a <feature>topic
                        set</feature>. You can use this element to group topic sets in output, and
                    determine the order in which topic sets type appear in the
                        <feature>documentation set</feature> table of contents. The order is set
                    using the
                    <config-setting>/spfe/doc-set/topic-set-type-order</config-setting>
                    element. There are no special limits or requirements on this value. You can use
                    any topic set type names that make sense in your environment.  The value must
                    match one of the values in the element
                    <config-setting>/spfe/doc-set/topic-set-type-order</config-setting>.</p>
            </description>
            <build-property/>
            <include-behavior>
                <p>The value in the current file takes precedence over values in imported files.</p>
            </include-behavior>
        </element-description>
        <element-description>
            <xpath>/spfe/doc-set/topic-set-type-order</xpath>
            <description>
                <p>A string specifying the order in which the topic set type appears in the table of contents for a documentation set. It consists of topic set type names separated by spaces. The topic set type name for a topic set is set by the <config-setting>/spfe/topic-set-type</config-setting> element.</p>
            </description>
            <build-property/>
            <include-behavior/>
        </element-description>
        <element-description>
            <xpath>/spfe/strings</xpath>
            <description>
                <p>A container element for a list of <config-setting>string</config-setting> elements that define <feature>strings</feature> used by the tools or in content.</p>
            </description>
            <build-property/>
            <include-behavior>
                <p>Merged.</p>
            </include-behavior>
        </element-description>
        <element-description>
            <xpath>/spfe/strings/string</xpath>
            <description>
                <p>Defines a <feature>string</feature> and gives it an ID. Strings may be used by both the build tools and in content. </p>
            </description>
            <build-property/>
            <include-behavior>
                <p>Added. Strings with matching IDs from included files are omitted.</p>
            </include-behavior>
            <attributes>
                <attribute>
                    <name>id</name>
                    <description>
                        <p>The ID of the string. The string id is used to insert the string into a script of a piece of content. The markup used to insert a string may vary from one document type to another. In <tool-name>EPPO-Simple</tool-name>, the <xml-element-name namespace-uri="http://spfeopentoolkit.org/spfe-ot/plugins/eppo-simple/schemas/authoring/generic-topic">string-ref</xml-element-name> element is used.</p>
                    </description>
                </attribute>
            </attributes>
        </element-description>
    </body>

</element-descriptions>
