<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<generic-topic xmlns="http://spfeopentoolkit.org/ns/spfe-docs"
    xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
    xsi:schemaLocation="http://spfeopentoolkit.org/ns/spfe-docs http://spfeopentoolkit.org/spfe-docs/topic-types/generic-topic/schemas/generic-topic.xsd">
 
    <head>
        <id>creating-a-content-set</id>
        <history>
            <revision>
                <date>2014-10-30</date>
                <author>jfmacdonald</author>
                <comment>New topic</comment>
                <status>In progress</status>
            </revision>
        </history>
        <index>
            <entry>
                <type>task</type>
                <term>content set</term>
            </entry>
            <entry>
                <type>task</type>
                <term>document set</term>
            </entry>
        </index>
    </head>
    <body>
        <title>Creating a new content set</title>

        <p> The SPFE Open Toolkit (SPFE-OT) builds a collection of web pages or other output format
            from a collection of topics that you specify in a content set.</p>
        
        <section>
            <title>Why do I need a content set?</title>
            <p>A content set is the master plan that the SPFE Open Toolkit will use to generate
            output content. You must have a content-set configuration file to to run the SPFE
            build system to create output.</p>
        </section> 
        
        <section>
            <title>What is a content set?</title>

            <p> A content set is the collection of <feature>topics</feature> that you specify in a
                content-set configuration file. The SPFE-OT build system uses the the content-set
                configuration file to collect the source content and process it as a whole to
                generate HTML or other output format. The configuration file doesn't list the topics
                directly but specifies one or more <feature>topic-sets</feature>. Each topic set has
                its own configuration file that <italic>does</italic> specify the topics it
                includes.</p>

            <p> Thus, to generate output using the SPFE-OT, you'll need a content-set configuration
                file that specifies one or more topic sets.</p>
        
        </section> 

        <section>
            <title>What decisions do I need to make when planning a content set?</title>

            <p> Before diving in, take a moment to consider how you organize topics and file
                locations will affect how you work and what you create. </p>

            <ul>
                <li><p>
                    <bold>Topics:</bold> Though each topic should be a complete, functional unit, topics 
                    do have affinites by addressing similar subjects. Users will appreciate when closely
                    related topics are easy to find. One way to associate topics is to place them in the
                    same topic set.
                </p></li>

                <li><p>
                    <bold>File locations:</bold> While you can include topic files in a topic set wherever
                    they may be in the file system, you'll find it much simpler to organize files that
                    belong to a topic set in a single folder.
                </p></li>
            </ul>
        
        </section> 
        
        <section>
            <title>How do I create a content-set configuration file?</title>
            <p>Create an XML file in the <feature>content set configuration</feature> structure and locate
            it in the same directory you will execute <task>builds</task>.</p>
        </section>

    </body> 
</generic-topic>
